hello this is learning English Pro and
my name is j I'm your online tuer and
guide welcome to the ultimate business
English Master Class whether you're
gearing up for a big presentation
navigating a virtual meeting or refining
your professional communication skills
this compilation master class has got
you covered in this master class you'll
find expert guidance on everything from
virtual meeting phrases to Advanced
interview techniques essential
vocabulary for sales and customer
service and even specialized ter terms
in finance real estate and AI if you
want to skip ahead to a lesson of your
choice all the lessons are timestamped
in the video description for easy
navigation so whether you're a season
professional or just starting your
business career this compilation is your
go-to resource for mastering the
language of business so grab a notebook
settle in and let's take your business
English to the next level today we're
tackling a highly relevant Topic in
today's business World Advan business
English for virtual meetings and remote
work with remote work becoming the norm
mastering the language and etiquette of
virtual meetings is more important than
ever whether you're leading a team
collaborating with colleagues or
presenting to clients this lesson will
equip you with the phrases and
strategies you need to communicate
effectively so if you're ready grab a
pen and paper and let's dive
in Virtual meetings and remote
communication are NOW essential parts of
the modern workplace whether you're
working from home managing a global team
or engaging with clients across
different time zones your ability to
communicate clearly and professionally
in English is crucial in this lesson
we'll cover the key phrases tips and
strategies to help you excel in this new
work
environment let's start with some
essential phrases that you'll need
during different stages of a virtual
meeting these phrases will help you
manage the meeting effectively engage
with participants and ensure that your
message is
clear the following phrases are useful
when you're starting the meeting these
are really good ways for opening the
meeting and setting the
agenda thank you all for joining today
let's start by reviewing the agenda
can everyone hear me clearly if you're
having trouble please let me know in the
chat let's move on to our next topic
which is facilitating discussions this
is how we can encourage participation
and manage the flow of
conversation I'd like to hear everyone's
thoughts on this please feel free to
unmute and share your input
let's go around the room James could you
start by giving us your
perspective meetings are all about
sharing information but what key phrases
can we use when we want to present ideas
data or updates in a virtual
meeting let me share my screen so you
can see the presentation
as you can see from this chart our sales
have increased by 15% this
quarter to ensure everyone is on the
same page here are some key phrases for
clarifying and confirming understanding
amongst
participants just to clarify are we all
in agreement on the next steps
can I confirm that the deadline for this
task is next
Friday managing technology in meetings
is never easy here are two useful
phrases you can use to address common
technical
problems it seems like there's a bit of
a lag could everyone try turning off
their video to improve the connection
I'm going to reshare my screen please
let me know if it's still not
visible the meeting is coming to a close
so here are some phrases for wrapping up
the discussion and outlining action
items before we close let's summarize
the key points and action items
thank you for your time today I'll send
it the meeting minutes and follow-up
tasks
shortly these phrases that we've just
covered are your toolkit for running
effective and professional virtual
meetings practice them to ensure you're
prepared for any
situation next let's discuss some key
strategies for remote communication
working remotely brings unique
challenges such as time zone differences
technology issues and maintaining team
cohesion here are some strategies to
help you overcome these challenges and
communicate
effectively when it comes to time
management always confirm the time zone
when scheduling meetings with
International colleagues
when it comes to speaking in English
avoid jargon or overly complex language
that might confuse non-native speakers
so keep it
simple it can be difficult to get to
know people in a virtual
environment you can start meetings with
a brief personal check-in or small talk
to maintain a connection
and use video whenever possible to
create a more personal
interaction when it comes to sharing
information use shared folders on
platforms like Google drive or Dropbox
to keep everyone on the same
page an important thing to do is to
summarize key points and action items in
follow-up emails after meetings to make
sure everyone's aware of what is
expected these strategies will help you
navigate the challenges of remote work
and ensure that your communication is
effective no matter where your team is
located let's recap what we've covered
today key phrases for managing virtual
meetings from start to
finish we also loed strategies for
Effective remote communication including
time management and clear document
ation at home I want you to practice
leading a virtual meeting using the
phrases and strategies we discussed
record yourself or practice with a
partner this is a great way to really
get involved in the learning process let
me know how you got on in the comments
below I'd love to hear from
you thank you for watching if youve had
this video helpful please give it a
thumbs up and don't forget to subscribe
to learning English Pro for more ADV
Advanced English lessons and stay tuned
for another business English lesson up
next we have 100 English phrases for
sales you'll learn lots of really useful
English sentences for dealing with
tricky customers and tricky situations I
hope you enjoy this lesson and remember
you're learning English like a pro with
learning English
Pro if you're working in sales or
customer service this video is going to
be a game Cher for you today we're
diving into 100 essential English
phrases that will help you handle every
aspect of a sales
interaction whether you're working in a
retail store handling phone inquiries or
even dealing with tricky customer
situation in this video we're going to
cover a wide range of topics including
engaging with customers negotiating
prices managing refunds essential
phrases for phone interactions and how
to deal with those tricky customers
professionally and
effectively this video is perfect for
anyone in sales or customer service
whether you're just starting out or
looking to refine your communication
skills even if English isn't your first
language these phrases will help you
sound confident and professional in any
sales scenario and stay tuned after this
lesson for even more business English
vocabulary you'll learn lots of phrases
for different work scenarios in context
this is learning English Pro where you
can learn English like a pro let's get
started on our English lesson the phrase
our first topic is greeting
customers welcome how can I assist you
today good morning what brings you in
today hello is there anything specific
you're looking for
hi there need help finding
something good afternoon how can I help
make your shopping
easier in our next batch of phrases we
will look at how to engage with
customers is this your first time
shopping with us
are you shopping for yourself or a gift
today what kind of product are you
interested
in is there any particular style or
color you're looking
for may I suggest something that could
suit your needs
let's move on to our next topic
introducing products to a
customer this is one of our most popular
items let me show you some of our best
sellers this product just came in it's
very popular
we have a new collection that might
interest
you this item is highly recommended by
our
customers let's explore some phrases on
how we might advise a customer on
choice this product offers great value
for its
price if you're looking for durability
this would be an excellent
choice based on your needs I'd recommend
this
one this model has excellent reviews
from other
customers for your specific requirements
I think this option would work
best handling price negotiations can be
very tricky here's some phrases to make
it a lot
easier I understand your budget concerns
let's see what we can work
out I might be able to offer you a
discount on this it
if you purchase more than one I can
offer you a special
deal this is the best price we can offer
for this
quality we can consider a price
adjustment if you're buying in
bulk let's move on to phrases you can
use when closing the
sale would you like to proceed with this
item shall I get this ready for
you are you ready to check
out is there anything else you would
like to add to your purchase
I can have this wrapped up for you if
you're
ready boost your sales by learning how
to suggest additional products and
services
effectively this product pairs well with
the one you're
purchasing we also have a special offer
on this related item
would you be interested in an extended
warranty many customers who bought this
also purchased this
accessory you might want to consider
this additional
feature our next topic is handling
objections here you can equip yourself
with phrases that address customer
concerns and turn objections into
opportunities I understand your concern
let me explain why this product is worth
the
price this model might be a better fish
for your
needs let me show you a different option
that might be more suitable
we have a satisfaction guarantee if
you're not happy with your
purchase I can assure you this is a
quality
product let's move on handle difficult
situations with Grace using these
phrases tailored for managing tricky
customers
I apologize for any inconvenience let me
see how I can
help I understand you're upset let's
find a solution
together I'm here to help what can I do
to resolve this
issue let me get my manager to assist
with this situation
I appreciate your patience I'll make
sure this is handled
properly next up learn the best phrases
for processing refunds and returns while
maintaining customer
satisfaction do you have a receipt for
this
return I'm sorry this didn't meet your
expectations let's process your
refund would you like to exchange this
for something
else let me check at our return policy
and assist
you we can issue a refund to your
original payment
method our next batch of phrases will
help you manage phone increas
professionally ensuring a smooth
experience for
customers thank you for calling the
clothing store how can I assist
you let me check that information for
you can you please hold for a
moment I can answer any questions you
have have about our
products would you like me to place this
item on hold for
you I'll make sure that we have it in
stock before you come
in in our next topic you can get
equipped with essential phrases for
taking bookings and managing
appointments over the phone
thank you for calling how can I help you
with your booking
today can I confirm the date and time
for your
appointment let me check our schedule
and find the best time for
you would you like a reminder call or
email for your appointment
I've booked your appointment see you
then our next batch of phrases will help
you ensure seamless communication for
efficiently transferring calls to the
right
Department please hold while I transfer
your
call let me connect you with the right
Department
I'm transferring you to our specialist
please
hold I'll make sure you're connected
with someone who can
help one moment while I direct your
call in our next topic thanking the
customer I'll show you how to express
your gratitude and a positive Lasting
Impression with some simple yet powerful
thank you
phrases thank you for shopping with
us we appreciate your business have a
great
day thank you for your purchase we hope
to see you again
soon it was a pleasure as assisting you
today we look forward to your next
visit keep your customers happy and
loyal by mastering these phrases for
excellent after sales
service how has your purchase been
working out for
you is there anything else we can assist
you with
if you have any issues please don't
hesitate to contact
us we offer Support Services if you need
any help with your
product thank you for your feedback it
helps us improve our
service earlier in the lesson we covered
some phrases relating to refund
in our next topic we'll be navigating
challenging refund situations with
phrases that aim to resolve the issues
amicably I understand you're not happy
with the product let's find a
solution I apologize for the
inconvenience let me see what we can
do we can offer store credit if that
works better for
you I'll need to check with my manager
on this
refund we value your satisfaction and
I'll make sure we address this
properly with our next set of phrases
you'll be able to advise your customers
on great product pair to make sure their
products and purchases last longer for
them
to keep this product in the best
condition I recommend using this care
product this item requires special
handling let me show you
how you can extend the life of this
product by following these
steps we offer a maintenance service for
this
product here are some tips to help you
get the most out of your
purchase stay connected with your
customers by using the next set of
phrases to follow up on orders and
ensure
satisfaction I'm calling to update you
on your order status
your order is ready for pickup when
would you like to collect
it we've shipped your order and it
should arrive by
Friday I'm following up to ensure you
received your
order if you have any questions about
your order feel free to to reach
out encouraging customers to return with
the next set of phrases help promote
loyalty and repeat
business we have a special offer for
returning
customers you're eligible for a loyalty
discount on your next purchase
thank you for your continued business we
appreciate
it we'd love to see you back soon here's
a coupon for your next
visit join our Rewards program and enjoy
exclusive
benefits in our final topic learn how to
respond to price inquiries with
confidence using these essential
phrases this product is currently priced
at
$2 we offer price matching with our
competitors this item is on sale for a
limited
time I can provide a quote if you're
looking to purchase multiple
items our prices are competitive and we
offer excellent
value a great sales professional is
confident and pathetic and knowledgeable
they know how to connect with customers
provide tailor advice and handle
challenges with Grace by practicing
these 100 essential English phrases for
sales you'll become great at greeting
customers advising them on choices
handling tricky situations and following
up on orders all of the phrases will
help you communicate more effectively
and professionally if you've enjoyed
this lesson make sure to like comment
subscribe and share with the friend
don't go anywhere because coming up next
we have more professional business
English with my lesson on interview
techniques and after that there's even
more lessons lined up for you this is
learning English Pro and you're learning
English like a
pro in today's lesson we're heading back
to business English with conversation
and the topic is interview
skills today we'll be going through
three different interview scenarios to
help you improve your English speaking
skills I've chosen three types of jobs a
store assistant a restaurant waiter and
finally a financial analyst
the last interview is more advanced so
stick around for a bit of a challenge
now let's dive into the interviews pay
close attention to how the candidates
respond to each question and how they
interact with the interviewer and later
we'll take a look at the key qualities
of each successful
interview these interviews will have an
interviewer this is the person who asks
the questions in a job interview in our
examples the interviewer is the person
representing the company or
organization an interviewee is the
person who answers the questions this is
the candidate applying for the job in
our first scenario the interviewer is
Miss Smith she is the owner of a
clothing
boutique our interviewee is John Roberts
and the job he is applying for is a
store assistant let's check out the
interview hi Mr Roberts thank you for
coming in today how are
you hi I'm doing well thank you it's
great to be
here wonderful let's get started have
you worked in retail
before yes I have I worked as a sales
associate at a department store for
about 2 years I assisted customers manag
inventory and handled the register I
also helped with merchandising and
setting up
displays that's good to hear how do you
handle a busy day at the
store I stay calm and focused I
prioritize helping customers first and
make sure the store stays organized I'm
used to multitasking and working
efficiently even when it gets hectic
excellent customer service is very
important to us how do you ensure
customers have a positive
experience I always greet customers with
a smile and make sure they feel welcome
I listen carefully to what they're
looking for and offer personalized
assistance my goal is to help them find
exactly what they need and to leave the
store
happy that's exactly what we're looking
for why are you interested in working at
our
Boutique I've always had an interest in
fashion and I love the Unique Style your
boutique offers I'm excited about the
opportunity to work in a more
specialized environment where I can
really connect with customers and share
my passion for
clothing thank you Mr Roberts you seem
like a great fish we'll be in touch soon
thank you for the opportunity I look
forward to hearing from
you have a great
day you
to our next interview is for the job of
a restaurant waiter the interviewer is
Mrs Sharma a restaurant owner and the
interviewee is Tom Turner let's see how
it
goes hi Miss Mr Turner thanks for coming
in today how are
you hi I'm doing well thank you I
appreciate the opportunity to be
here glad to hear that so do you have
any experience working in the food
service
industry yes I do I've worked as a waer
for the past three years at a family
restaurant my responsibilities included
taking orders serving food handling
payments and ensuring guests had a great
dining experience I also assisted with
setting up and closing the
restaurant that sounds great how do you
handle working during peak hours when
the restaurant is very
busy I thrive in a fast-pace environment
I stay organized by prioritizing tasks
and maintaining a positive attitude I
make sure to communicate clearly with
the kitchen and my colleagues so
everything runs smoothly and customers
are
satisfied excellent customer
satisfaction is key here how do you make
sure guests feel welcome and taken care
of I always greet guests warmly and make
sure to be attentive to their needs I
listen carefully to any special requests
and ensure their orders are accurate my
goal is to create a comfortable and
enjoyable dining experience for
everyone that's exactly what we're
looking for here why do you want to work
at our
restaurant I've heard great things about
your restaurant's reputation for quality
and service I'm passionate about food
and enjoy interacting with people so I'm
excited about the chance to work in such
a well-regarded establishment where I
can contribute to a team that values
customer service
thank you Mr Turner I appreciate your
enthusiasm and experience we'll be in
touch
soon thank you for considering me I'm
looking forward to hearing from
you have a wonderful
day you
too our third interview is for the job
of financial analyst the interviewer is
a hatte your manager called Miss Collins
and the the interviewee is Daniel
Davis this interview is a lot more
advanced than the previous two so pay
attention good afternoon Mr Davis thank
you for coming in today how are
you good afternoon I'm doing well thank
you I'm glad to be
here wonderful let's get started could
you tell me about your experience in the
finance industry and how it relates to
the role of a financial
analyst certainly I have a master's
degree in finance and over four years of
experience working as a junior Financial
Analyst at a midsized investment firm in
my previous role I was responsible for
analyzing financial data preparing
detailed reports and assisting in the
creation of Financial
models I've worked closely with senior
analysts on investment strategies and
have a strong foundation in both
quantitative analysis and financial
forecasting that sounds like a solid
background how do you approach complex
financial problems especially when
dealing with large data
sets I'm a strong strong believer in
methodical problem solving I start by
breaking down the problem into smaller
manageable Parts I utilize Advanced
Excel functions and I'm proficient with
software like SQL and python for data
analysis by organizing the data and
using statistical methods I can identify
Trends and patterns that inform my
recommendations I also make sure to
double check my work to ensure accuracy
before presenting my
findings that's exactly the kind of
attention to detail we value can you
describe a time when your analysis
directly impacted a business
decision certainly in my last position I
conducted a thorough analysis of a
potential investment in a new market my
data indicated that the initial
projections were overly optimistic and I
presented an alternative analysis that
showed a more moderate growth
scenario based on my findings the
management decided to proceed with a
scaled down investment which ultimately
resulted in a more sustainable growth
trajectory for the
firm that's impressive and shows strong
analytical thinking what Drew you to
apply for this position at our
company I've always admired your
company's reputation for innovation in
the finance industry and your commitment
to ethical investment practices I'm
excited about the opportunity to
contribute to a company that values both
Cutting Edge Financial strategies and
corporate
responsibility I believe my skills
experience will allow me to make a
meaningful contribution to your
team thank you Mr Davis I'm very
impressed with your qualifications and
approach we'll be in touch with you
shortly thank you for the opportunity
Miss Collins I look forward to hearing
from
you have a great
day you too
the three interviews that you've just
listened to all display candidates that
did really well but what did they do
correctly they were able to talk about
their relevant experience each candidate
clearly communicated their previous work
experience related to the job they were
applying
for each candidate also had clear
communication they answered questions
concisely and directly
ensuring their responses were easy to
understand a positive attitude is really
helpful in an interview the candidates
maintained a positive and enthusiastic
tone throughout the interview showing
eagerness for the
role each candidate also displayed
problemsolving skills they demonstrated
their ability to handle challenges
specific to the job such as multitasking
or working under pressure
and finally each candidate showed an
alignment with the company
values they expressed a genuine interest
in the company and showed how their
values aligned with the organization's
Mission so there you have it that's our
first lesson on learning English Pro on
business conversation in interviews
there's lots more scenarios I can cover
so if you want more lessons like this
one make sure to like share comment and
rewatch The videos a few times that will
definitely help and up next stay tuned
because we have a lesson on negotiations
which I previously published on my
channel and after that there's even more
business English you can really learn
English like a pro with learning English
Pro today we're diving into a critical
area Advanced business English for
negotiations whether you're negotiating
a contract closing a deal or managing
conflicts this lesson will equip you
with the phrases and strategies you need
to
excel negotiation is a vital skill in
business whether you're working on a
multi-million doll deal or simply
resolving a conflict it requires not
only strategic thinking but also a
strong command of language in today's
lesson we'll cover essential phrases
strategies and tips for Effective
business
negotiations here's what we'll
cover key phrases for different stages
of
negotiation how to make and respond to
offers strategies for handling
objections and closing the
deal let's start with key phrases you'll
need during different stages of a
negotiation these phrases will help you
navigate through the process process
smoothly and
assertively when opening the negotiation
you want to establish a professional
tone and set the
agenda our first phrase
is thank you for meeting with us today
I'd like to start by outlining our
objectives for this
negotiation another way we could say
this is before we begin let's agree on
the agenda for today today's
discussion next up let's look at
presenting your position here we really
want to State clearly what the terms and
conditions are let's take a look at two
example
phrases our main priority is securing a
long-term partnership that benefits both
parties we propose a three-year contract
with the fixed pricing
structure if if you present your terms
and conditions like these phrases you'll
come across as really
professional next up let's take a look
at some phrases for making offers and
counter offers this is the core of the
negotiation
process in light of your proposal we're
willing to offer a 5% discount on bulk
orders let's try a different phrase
we appreciate your offer but we need a
more flexible payment schedule to
proceed let's move on to clarifying and
confirming terms this process is all
about ensuring both parties understand
and agree on the
details here's our first
example just to clarify you're
suggesting a delivery schedule that
begins in the second quarter correct
to confirm both parties are in agreement
on the revised terms of
service these two phrases are really
great at making sure that everyone is
very clear on the details of the
agreement in our next section handling
objections we'll be addressing concerns
and pushing the negotiation forward so
if a party has an issue with one of the
terms or conditions you could say I
understand your concerns about the
timeline but we can expedite the process
with additional
resources or how about while I see your
point I believe the current terms
already offer significant
value with these phrases you can soothe
concerns and reaffirm your
position next up we have closing the
deal these phrases are all about
finalizing the agreement and setting the
stage for
implementation I think we've reached a
mutually beneficial agreement let's move
forward with the
contract if there are no further
concerns we can proceed with drafting
the final
agreement these phrases will help you
guide the negotiation process from the
opening discussion to the closing deal
practice them to build your confidence
and
fluency next let's focus on making and
responding to offers this is where your
language needs to be precise persuasive
and
flexible when it comes to making an
offer we could say given the current
market conditions we believe a 10%
increase in price is
Justified let's try a different phrase
we're prepared to offer extended payment
terms if you can commit to larger order
volumes and how about responding to an
offer let's check out these two key
phrases while your offer is competitive
we would need a further reduction to
align with our
budget your proposal is intriguing but
we'd like to explore options for faster
delivery remember how you frame your
offer or counter offer can significantly
impact the outcome of the
negotiation use these phrases to ensure
your offers are clear and
persuasive negotiations often involve
objections and challenges but how you
handle these can make or break the deal
let's look at some strategies and
phrases for overcoming objections and
closing the
deal for handling an objection you could
say
I understand that the price may seem
high but let's consider the long-term
savings this solution
provides another phrase for handling
objections could be I see your concern
about the timeline but we can offer
additional support to ensure deadlines
are
met for closing the deal I have two
great
phrases it seems like we've addressed
all the key issues shall we finalize the
agreement and our last phrase for this
lesson I'm confident this agreement will
be beneficial for both of us let's
proceed with the
contract closing the deal is about
summarizing the agreed terms and
expressing confidence in the outcome
these phrases will help you conclude
negotiations effectively and leave a
positive
impression let's recap what we've
covered today key phrases for opening NE
negociating and closing
deals strategies for making and
responding to
offers techniques for handling
objections and ensuring a successful
outcome thank you so much for watching
if you found this video helpful please
give it a thumbs up and don't forget to
subscribe to learning English Pro for
more professional English lessons and
don't go anywhere up next we have a
lesson on how to transform 50 basic
English phrases into professional
business English remember this is
learning English Pro where you learn
English like a
pro welcome to today's lesson on
transforming everyday English into
business English in this session we'll
go over common phrases and show you how
to elevate them for a professional
setting okay let's get started our first
basic English phrase is can you do this
in business environment it's important
to be polite and respectful when making
requests the phrase could you please
handle this is more courteous and
professional using please adds a level
of politeness and handle this task
sounds more formal than do
this could you please handle this
task our next basic phrase is I don't
know saying I don't know can come across
as dismissive or unhelpful in business
it's crucial to show initiative and
willingness to provide Answers by saying
I'm not certain at the moment but I'll
find out you're acknowledging your
current lack of knowledge but also
demonstrating a proactive attitude to
seek out the
information I'm not certain at the
moment but I'll find out
our third example of basic English is
I'll do it later in business it's vital
to show you are managing your time
effectively and taking tasks
seriously the phrase I'll prioritize
this and complete it as soon as possible
indicates that you understand the
importance of the task and are committed
to addressing it promptly which conveys
a strong work ethic I'll prioritize this
and complete it as soon as
possible our next phrase is that's not
my job responding with this can seem
quite uncooperative in a professional
setting it's better to show a
collaborative Spirit saying I'll see if
I can assist or find the appropriate
person to help demonstrates a
willingness to support your team and
find a solution even if the task isn't
directly within your resp
responsibilities I'll see if I can
assist or find the appropriate person to
help the phrase I can't help you might
leave the person feeling abandoned in
business providing a solution or an
alternative is Key by saying let me
direct you to someone who can assist you
you're offering a constructive response
showing that you care about the person's
needs and are committed to finding help
for them let me direct you to someone
who can assist
you saying I'm busy right now might seem
abrupt instead you could try I'm
currently engaged in another task can we
schedule a time to discuss this by
explaining your current engagement and
suggesting a specific time to address
the issue you show that you value the
person's concern while managing your
priorities
effectively I'm currently engaged in
another task can we schedule a time to
discuss
this the phrase it's not good enough can
sound harsh and
demotivating saying this needs
Improvement to meet our standards is
more constructive and sets a clear
expectation encouraging better
performance without being overly
critical this needs Improvement to meet
our standards
saying I need a raise is very direct and
seems a bit blunt by saying I'd like to
discuss my compensation based on my
performance and contributions we are
better framing a discussion about your
performance and it shows you are open to
dialogue and are basing your request on
Merit which is more likely to be well
received I'd like to discuss my
compensation based on my performance and
contributions saying this is a bad idea
can be discouraging instead we could say
I'm concerned about the potential risks
can we evaluate the
Alternatives by saying this you are
showing that you can consider different
perspectives and are willing to find the
best solution together as a
team I'm concerned about the potential
risks can we evaluate the
Alternatives saying I don't like it is
subjective and
unhelpful instead we could say I have
some reservations can we explore other
options by using this phrase you are
providing a constructive critique and
opening the door for discussion and
Improvement I have some reservations can
we explore other options
why did you do that can come across as
accusatory instead we could say can you
explain your reasoning behind this
action by saying this you show that you
are seeking to understand the thought
process behind a decision which is much
more respectful and
productive can you explain your
reasoning behind this action
simply stating that's wrong is not
helpful our business English
transformation is there seems to be an
error let's review it together in this
way you are pointing out that there
seems to be an error and suggesting a
joint review encourages collaboration
and problem
solving there seems to be an error let's
review it
together saying I'll try can sound
uncertain I will do my best to
accomplish this shows commitment and
confidence in your ability to complete
the
task I will do my best to accomplish
this it's not my fault sounds like
you're blaming others and it can create
Conflict by saying let's identify what
went wrong and how we can resolve it you
are showing that you Foster a more
cooperative and solution orientated
environment let's identify what went
wrong and how we can resolve
it our 15th example is I need more
time instead we could say I require
additional time to complete this
thoroughly requesting more time in a
straightforward manner can be perceived
as a lack of planning by explaining that
additional time is needed to ensure Thor
completion you emphasize your commitment
to quality work I require additional
time to complete this
thoroughly saying I don't understand can
feel abrupt it's much better to say
could you clarify that for me asking for
clarification is more polite and shows
that you are actively seeking to
comprehend the
information could you clarify that for
me
next up our basic English phrase is I'll
be late in business English we could say
I may not arrive on time I'll keep you
updated informing someone that you'll be
late is important but adding that you'll
keep them updated shows that you are
considerate of their time and
responsibilities I may not arrive on
time I'll keep you
updated let's move on to I'm leaving
early instead we should say I need to
leave early today I'll ensure all my
tasks are
covered when leaving early it's
courteous to assure that your
responsibilities are managed this
statement shows that you are responsible
and considerate of your work
commitments I need to leave early today
I'll ensure all my tasks are
covered saying we can't do that shows an
outright refusal and it can shut down
dialogue instead we could say that may
not be feasible can we consider an
alternative
approach by suggesting that something
may not be feasible and proposing
Alternatives you keep the conversation
open and
constructive that may not be feasible
can we consider an alternative
approach our basic sentence is you
didn't tell me we will say instead in
business English I wasn't informed about
this can we discuss it
now by using the basic English version
you are kind of accusing someone of not
informing you and it can create
tension by using the business English
version you can show that you are aiming
to resolve the issue without assigning
blame I wasn't informed about this can
we discuss it
now saying that's impossible can be
discouraging instead you should say that
seems highly challenging let's consider
how we might approach it differently
this phrase shows you have a willingness
to find
solutions that seems highly challenging
let's consider how we might approach it
differently
telling someone to hurry up can be
perceived as rude instead we could say
could you expedite this process this is
much more polite and maintains
professionalism could you expedite this
process stop bothering me is dismissive
and rude instead we could say could you
please address this later this is more
respectful and maintains a positive tone
could you please address this
later saying this is boring can be
demotivating instead say this could be
more engaging can we make some
adjustments this phrase comes across as
being constructive and encouraging of
improvement this could be more engaging
can we make some
adjustments demanding action with do it
now can be
abrasive please address this immediately
is a more polite yet urgent request
maintaining
respect please address this
immediately it's okay to say that you
made a mistake but in a business sense
it's better to say I need to correct an
error let's address it together this
shows teamwork and a commitment to
resolving issues
collaboratively I need to correct an
error let's address it
together saying it's too expensive can
sound
blunt instead we should say this exceeds
our budget can we explore more coste
effective
options this phrase shows Financial
prudence and problem
solving this exceeds our budget can we
explore more coste effective
options saying I need help might seem
abrupt instead we should say could you
assist me with this task this is more
polite and specific which is appreciated
in a business
environment could you assist me with
this task
admitting forgetfulness with I forgot
might come across as
careless instead you should say it
slipped my mind I apologize for the
oversight this shows being able to take
responsibility and a commitment to
making things right it slipped my mind I
apologize for the
oversight saying it's not ready can
sound unprepared instead you should say
this is still in progress I will inform
you once it's complete this sentence
shows that you are actively working on
something and you're managing someone
else's
expectations this is still in progress I
will inform you once it's
complete next up let's change the basic
English phrase I can't make it to I
won't be able to attend can we
reschedule
informing someone that you can't attend
is necessary but offering to reschedule
shows that you value the commitment and
are looking for a way to make it work I
won't be able to attend can we
reschedule while that's great is
positive this is excellent work is more
specific and gives clearer recognition
of effort and
achievement this is excellent work
saying I'm sorry is often enough but in
a business context saying I apologize
for any inconvenience cause shows a more
formal acknowledgment of the
impact I apologize for any inconvenience
caused saying no problem is
informal instead we should say it's not
an issue this is more more professional
and it reassures someone that their
request or action is
acceptable it's not an
issue suggesting a meeting with let's
meet can seem
informal can we schedule a meeting is
more professional and indicates respect
for the other person's
time can we schedule a
meeting while you're welcome is very
polite it was my pleasure as a touch of
formality and warmth which is often
appreciated in business
Communications it was my
pleasure thanks is casual and can be
seen as less sincere thank you very much
is more formal and expresses greater
appreciation thank you very
much saying I don't agree is quite
Direct
and might lead to conflict instead we
could say I have a different perspective
on the matter by saying this you are
allowing for a more open and respectful
dialogue I have a different perspective
on this
matter saying this is urgent is direct
but can create unnecessary stress this
requires immediate attention is a more
professional way to convey urgency
without sounding
alarmist this requires immediate
attention saying it's too late is very
final and can close off discussion
instead we could say we missed the
deadline let's evaluate our options this
phrase comes across as being more
constructive and solution oriented we
missed the deadline let's evaluate our
options
saying I'm not interested can come
across as
dismissive instead you should say I
don't see the value in this at the
moment by saying this you leave room for
further discussion if the situation
changes I don't see value in this at the
moment our next basic English phrase is
what's the point this can come across as
cynical or dismissive
instead you should say could you explain
the purpose behind this this phrase is
more respectful and encourages a clearer
understanding could you explain the
purpose behind
this while good job is positive well
done is slightly more formal and can
convey greater sincerity in
acknowledging someone's work well done
I'm on it is casual and can be
interpreted as less committed I'm
handling it now is more formal and
indicates that you are actively
addressing the task I'm handling it
now can you wait sounds abrupt and rude
could you please hold on for a moment is
more polite and shows respect for the
other person's time could you please
please hold on for a
moment saying this is a mess can seem
overly critical in business English we
would say this needs significant
Improvement this is more constructive
and focuses on the action needed this
needs significant
Improvement I'm done in sound informal
and rushed instead I have completed the
task is more formal and provides clear
communication about the work that is
finished I have completed the
task telling someone you're wrong is
quite
confrontational saying I believe there
might be a misunderstanding is much more
diplomatic and opens the door for
clarification I believe there might be a
misunderstanding saying that's not true
can sound
accusatory instead you should say I
think there's some
misinformation this is more tactful and
less likely to cause offense I think
there's some
misinformation and can you believe we're
already on our 50th and final phrase
let's go is informal that might seem a
bit too casual in a business setting
instead you should say let's proceed
this is much more professional and
conveys the same sense of moving
forward these examples highlight the
importance of being polite proactive and
solution oriented in a business
environment by refining your language
you can communicate more effectively and
professionally practice these
Transformations and you'll see a
significant Improvement in your business
interactions thank you so much for
watching and happy learning and today
we're diving back into the world of
business English and we'll cover a 100
essential phrases specifically tailored
for customer service
professionals customer service can be
incredibly challenging especially when
dealing with tricky situations like
handling complaints understanding angry
customers or even delivering bad news
this lesson is designed to equip you
with the precise language and phrases
you need to navigate these difficult
scenarios confidently and
professionally in my comprehensive
lesson we'll cover a difficult scenarios
like cold calling understanding an angry
customer apologizing for a big mistake
handling complaints and calming the
situation I'll even cover polite phrases
for dealing with rude customers and how
about if you have to say no to a
customer and deny them a product or
service
there are lots of topics to cover and
even more phrases so get ready to really
boost your English proficiency don't
forget to subscribe to learning English
Pro and hit the Bell icon to stay
updated on my latest
lessons our first topic is cold calling
and introducing yourself to
customers cold calling is the term we
use for reaching out to potential
customers who haven't previously
expressed interest in your product or
service
making a good first impression is
crucial let's explore some key phrases
to introduce yourself and your company
effectively good morning this is J from
learning English Pro how are you
today good morning this is J from
learning English Pro how are you today
hello I'm J calling from learning
English
Pro hello I'm jar calling from learning
Pro hi this is jar from learning English
Pro do you have a moment to
talk hi this is J from learning English
talk good afternoon my name is j and I'm
calling on behalf of learning English
Pro good afternoon my name is j and I'm
Pro hello this is J from learning
English Pro how are you doing
today hello this is J from learning
today hi I'm J from learning English Pro
I wanted to speak with you about English
lessons hi I'm jar from learning English
Pro I wanted to speak with you about
English lessons
good day my name is j and I'm reaching
out from learning English
Pro good day my name is j and I'm
reaching out from learning English
Pro hello this is J calling from
learning English Pro is now a good time
to
talk hello this is jar calling from
learning English Pro is now a good time
to
talk good morning I'm jar from learning
English Pro can I take a few minutes of
your
time good morning I'm J from learning
English Pro can I take a few minutes of
your
time hi I'm jar with learning English
Pro I wanted to discuss how we can help
your
business hi I'm jar with learning
English Pro I wanted to discuss how we
can help your
business let's move on to our next topic
which is understanding an angry
customer dealing with angry customers
requires empathy and patience here are
some essential phrases to help you
understand and calm things
down I understand you're upset and I'm
here to
help I understand you're upset and I'm
help I can see why you're
frustrated I can see why you're
frustrated your concern is completely
valid your concern is completely
valid let's see how we can resolve this
issue let's see how we can resolve this
issue
I apologize for any inconvenience
caused I apologize for any inconvenience
caused could you tell me more about what
happened could you tell me more about
what
happened I'm sorry for any trouble
you've experienced
I'm sorry for any trouble you've
experienced please explain the issue so
I can assist you
better please explain the issue so I can
assist you better
I'm here to listen and help resolve this
for
you I'm here to listen and help resolve
this for
you let's work together to find a
solution let's work together to find a
solution up next our topic is
apologizing for a bit mistake when
significant mistakes happen sincere
apologies are a must these phrases will
help you convey your regret and take
responsibility I deeply apologize for
this
mistake I deeply apologize for this
mistake we are very sorry sorry for the
error we are very sorry for the
error please accept our sincerest
apologies please accept our sincerest
apologies this this was entirely our
fault and I'm very
sorry this was entirely our fault and
I'm very
sorry we regret the inconvenience this
has
caused we regret the inconvenience this
has caused
I understand this is very frustrating
and I
apologize I understand this is very
frustrating and I
apologize I'm sorry for the significant
inconvenience I'm sorry for the
significant inconvenience
we apologize for any trouble this has
caused we apologize for any trouble this
has
caused this was a serious oversight on
our
part this was a serious oversight on our
part I assure you we are addressing this
issue
immediately I assure you we are
addressing this issue
immediately let's take a break from
dealing with these tricky situations and
focus on our next topic going above and
beyond being a customer service
Superstar exceeding customer
expectations can turn a negative
experience into a positive one let's
learn how to go above and beyond with
the next set of
phrases I'm here to ensure you have the
best experience
possible I'm here to ensure you have the
possible let me take care of that for
you right away
away let me take care of that for you
right
away I'll personally handle this issue
for
you I'll personally handle this issue
you I will make sure this is resolved
quickly I will make sure this is
resolved
quickly your satisfaction is my top
priority your satisfaction is my top
priority I'll go the extra mile to help
you I'll go the extra mile to help
you let me let me see how I can exceed
your
expectations let me see how I can exceed
expectations I'll make sure you're
completely
satisfied I'll make sure you're
satisfied I'll provide you with a
special offer for the inconvenience
I'll provide you with a special offer
for the
inconvenience I'm committed to making
this right for
you I'm committed to making this right
for
you our next topic is handling
complaints and calming the
situation handling complaints
effectively can diffuse tension and
resolve issues here are key phrases to
calm and reassure your
customers I apologize for the
inconvenience I apologize for the
inconvenience I'm sorry to hear that
you're facing this
issue I'm sorry to hear that you're
facing this
issue let me see how I can make this
right for
you let me see how I can make this right
for
you I understand your frustration and I
apologize I understand your frustration
and I apologize
we are sorry for any inconvenience
caused we are sorry for any
inconvenience
caused please accept our apologies for
this
situation please accept our apologies
for this situation
we apologize for the trouble you've
experienced we apologize for the trouble
you've
experienced I'm here to help resolve
this for
you I'm here to help resolve this for
you I'm very sorry for the inconvenience
I'm very sorry for the
inconvenience let's see what we can do
to solve this
problem let's see what we can do to
solve this
problem maintaining professionalism with
rude customers is essential in our sixth
topic polite phrases for dealing with
rude customers we will use polite
phrases to handle challenging
interactions
gracefully I understand your frustration
and I'm here to
help I understand your frustration and
I'm here to
help please allow me a moment to assist
you please allow me a moment to assist
you I appreciate your patience as we
work through
this I appreciate your patience as we
this let's work together to resolve this
issue let's work together to resolve
this issue
I apologize if there has been any
inconvenience I apologize if there has
been any
inconvenience I'm here to make things
right for
you I'm here to make things right for
you could you please explain the issue
in detail
could you please explain the issue in
detail thank you for bringing this to
our
attention thank you for bringing this to
attention I'm doing my best to help
resolve this for
you I'm doing my best to help resolve
this for
you I appreciate your
understanding I appreciate your
understanding our next topic is how to
deny a customer a service or product
saying no to a customer can be difficult
these phrases will help you deny
requests politely and professionally
unfortunately we're unable to fulfill
your request at this
time unfortunately we're unable to
fulfill your request at this
time I'm sorry but that service is not
available I'm sorry but that service is
not available
we apologize but we cannot provide that
product we apologize but we cannot
provide that
product due to company policy we are
unable to offer this
service due to company policy we are
unable to offer this service
service regrettably we don't have the
capacity to accommodate your
request regrettably we don't have the
request I understand your need but we
cannot fulfill it currently
I understand your need but we cannot
fulfill it
currently I apologize but this is not
something we can
do I apologize but this is not something
we can
do I'm sorry but we cannot provide this
at the moment
I'm sorry but we cannot provide this at
the
moment unfortunately this request is
outside of our
policy unfortunately this request is
policy we are unable to offer that
product right
now we are on unable to offer that
service right
now our next topic is explaining bad
news to
customers delivering bad news is never
easy but with our next set of phrases
you will be able to communicate
unfortunate information with empathy and
Clarity I regret to inform you that
there has been an issue
I regret to inform you that there has
been an
issue unfortunately we have encountered
a
problem unfortunately we have
encountered a
problem I'm sorry to say that there will
be a delay
I'm sorry to say that there will be a
delay we regret to inform you that we
cannot proceed as
planned we regret to inform you that we
planned I apologize but there has been
an
error I apologize but there has been an
error
unfortunately we are unable to complete
your
request unfortunately we are unable to
complete your
request we have identified an issue and
are working to resolve
it we have identified an issue and are
working to resolve it
I'm afraid there has been a
setback I'm afraid there has been a
setback we apologize for any
inconvenience caused by this
news we apologize for any inconvenience
caused by this news
unfortunately we must inform you of this
problem unfortunately we must inform you
of this
problem our second last topic is
follow-up and
Confirmation following up and confirming
details shows customers you care use
these phrases is to ensure clear and
continuous
communication I'll follow up with you in
a few
days I'll follow up with you in a few
days can I confirm your details for
followup can I confirm your details for
followup
I'll send you a confirmation email
shortly I'll send you a confirmation
email
shortly please let us know if the issue
persists please let us know if the issue
persists I'll check back with you to
ensure everything is resolved
I'll check back with you to ensure
everything is
resolved is it okay if I contact you for
further
updates is it okay if I contact you for
updates we'll keep you updated on the
progress
we'll keep you updated on the
progress I'll make sure to follow up on
this
matter I'll make sure to follow up on
matter we'll confirm once the issue is
resolved we'll confirm once the issue is
resolved
please expect a follow-up call
soon please expect a follow-up email
soon ending a customer service
interaction on a positive note is
important in our final topic closing the
interaction these phrases will help you
close your conversations professionally
thank you for your time and
patience thank you for your time and
patience it was a pleasure assisting you
today it was a pleasure assisting you
today have a great
day have a great
day thank you thank you for choosing
learning English
pro thank you for choosing learning
English
Pro we appreciate your
business we appreciate your
business don't hesitate to contact us
[Music]
again don't hesitate to contact us again
take care and thank you for
calling take care and thank you for
calling we look forward to serving you
again we look forward to serving you
again thank you and
goodbye thank you and goodbye
have a wonderful day
ahead have a wonderful day
ahead thank you for joining me on this
English master class on essential
customer service phrases I hope you
found them helpful and feel more
confident handling various customer
interactions remember practice makes
perfect keep using these phrases to
enhance your communication
skills in this lesson we'll be learning
effective communication for call center
agents in today's fast-paced customer
service environment the ability to
communicate clearly and efficiently is
essential whether you're handling a
customer's first inquiry resolving a
technical issue or managing a complaint
the right words can make all the
difference in this lesson we'll cover a
100 essential phrases that every call
center professional should have in their
toolkit these phrases are grouped into
common topics and scenarios you'll
encounter daily from greeting customers
to providing technical support and
handling complaints by mastering these
phrases you'll be better equipped to
provide exceptional service build strong
customer relationships and handle a wide
range of situations with confidence and
professionalism so let's get started and
enhance our communication skills to
ensure every customer interaction is
positive and
productive our first topic is greeting
and
introduction good morning this is J from
learning English Pro how can I assist
you
[Music]
today good morning this is jar from
learning English Pro how can I assist
you today
thank you for calling learning English
Pro my name is j how can I help
you thank you for calling learning
English Pro my name is jar how can I
help
you hello this is jar from learning
English Pro what can I do for you
today hello this is jar from learning
today hi you've reached learning English
Pro how may I assist
you hi you've reached learning English
Pro how may I assist you
welcome to learning English Pro my name
is j how can I assist you
[Music]
today welcome to learning English Pro my
name is j how can I assist you
today thank you for calling learning
English Pro how may I help you
today hello and thank you for calling
learning English Pro this is j how can I
[Music]
assist hello and thank you for calling
learning English Pro this is jar how can
I
assist good afternoon thank you for
contacting learning English Pro
how may I help you
today good afternoon thank you for
contacting learning English Pro how may
I help you
today thank you for calling learning
English Pro my name is j how can I
assist you
today thank you for calling learning
English Pro my name is jar how can I
assist you today
hi this is jar from learning English Pro
how can I be of service to you
today hi this is jar from learning
English Pro how can I be of service to
you
today so lots of phrases there for
greeting and introducing yourself and
your company to a potential customer
let's move on to phrases on how we can
identify their customer and discover
what their needs might
be can I have your name and account
number
please can I have your name and account
please may I know how I can assist you
today may I know how I can assist you
today what seems to be the problem
you're
experiencing what seems to be the
problem you're
experiencing can you please provide more
details about your
issue can you please provide more
details about your issue
how can I help resolve your issue
today how can I help resolve your issue
today could you please describe the
issue you're
facing could you please describe the
facing let's start with your name and
the nature of your
call let's start with your name and the
nature of your
call how can I assist you with your
account
today how can I assist you with your
today can you give me me a bit more
information about the
problem can you give me a bit more
problem what specific issue are you
having with our
service what specific issue are you
having with our product
very good let's move on to our next
topic which is confirming and verifying
information let me verify your details
please let me verify your details
please can you confirm your address and
phone number for
me can you confirm your address and
me may I have your email for
verification
purposes may I have your email for
purposes I'll need to verify some
information before we
proceed I'll need to verify some
proceed can you please confirm your date
of
birth can you please confirm your date
birth I need to verify your identity can
you provide your account number
I need to verify your identity can you
provide your account
number please confirm the last four
digits of your Social Security
number could you spell your last name
for me please
could you spell your last name for me
please can you confirm the last
transaction on your
account can you confirm the last
account let me check our records to
verify your account details
let me check our records to verify your
account
details wonderful you're doing great
it's time for our next topic listening
and having empathy for
customers I understand your frustration
let me see how I can
help I understand your frustration let
me see how I can help
help I'm sorry to hear that you're
experiencing this
issue I'm sorry to hear that you're
issue I can understand how this might be
frustrating for
you I can understand how this might be
frustrating for you
thank you for bringing this to our
attention thank you for bringing this to
our
attention I apologize for any
inconvenience this may have
caused I apologize for any inconvenience
this may have caused
I appreciate your patience as we work
through
this I appreciate your patience as we
work through
this I'm here to help and I will do my
best to resolve this for
you I'm here to help and I will do my
best to resolve this for you
I understand your concern let's see what
we can
do I understand your concern let's see
what we can
do I'm sorry that you're facing this
issue let's work on fixing
it I'm sorry that you're facing this
issue let's work on fixing it
thank you for your understanding as we
resolve this
matter thank you for your understanding
as we resolve this
matter so some very handy phrases there
for dealing with people who are annoyed
for our next topic let's look at phrases
relating to providing Solutions and
assistance to customers
here's what we can do to resolve your
issue here's what we can do to resolve
your
issue I can assist you with that right
away I can assist you with that right
away let me walk you through the steps
to fix this
let me walk you through the steps to fix
this we can offer you a replacement or
refund we can offer you a replacement or
refund I will escalate this issue with
our technical team
I will escalate this issue with our
technical
team I'll make sure this gets resolved
as soon as
possible I'll make sure this gets
resolved as soon as
possible let me guide you through the
process to resolve
this let me guide you through the
process to resolve this
we can schedule a technician to visit
your
location we can schedule a technician to
visit your
location I will update your account with
the necessary
changes I will update your account with
changes let me provide you with some
troubleshooting
steps let me provide you with some
steps let's take a look at some phrases
relating to handling complaints
I'm sorry you're not satisfied with our
service I'm sorry you're not satisfied
with our
service let's see how we can make this
right let's see how we can make this
right I apologize for any inconvenience
this may have caused
you I apologize for any inconvenience
you I'll do my best to resolve this
issue for
you we value your feedback and we'll use
it to improve our
services we value your feedback and will
use it to improve our
services thank you for bringing this to
our
attention thank you for bringing this to
attention I can understand why you're
upset
let's find a
solution I can understand why you're
upset let's find a
solution I will personally ensure this
is taken care
of I will personally ensure this is
taken care
of I'll escalate your complaint to to
our management
team I'll escalate your complaint to our
management
team I apologize for any trouble you've
experienced I apologize for any trouble
you've
experienced in our next section
explaining policies and procedures our
list list of phrases is something that
you can use to integrate them with your
company's specific policies and
procedures so let's take a look at the
first phrase our policy states
that so I'll give you an example for
this first phrase our policy states that
returns must be made within 30 days of
purchase
so I've used this phrase to communicate
a particular rule to a
customer so for the next phrases why not
try integrating some of your own
company's policies and procedures with
each
phrase according to our
records according to our records
the procedure for this is as
follows the procedure for this is as
follows let me explain how this
works let me explain how this
works here's what you need to do next
here's what you need to do
next our guidelines require
that our guidelines require
that this is the standard procedure
for this is the standard procedure for
I can clarify our policy on that for
you I can clarify our policy on that for
you the next step is
to the next step is
to this is what we'll need to do to
resolve
this this this is what we'll need to do
to resolve
this I hope you're enjoying this lesson
so far our next topic is technical
support have you tried restarting your
device have you tried restarting your
device can you describe the error
message you're
seeing can you describe the error
seeing I'll guide you through the
troubleshooting
steps I'll guide you through the
steps let's check your internet
connection first
let's check your internet connection
first can you confirm if the device is
plugged
in can you confirm if the device is
in please follow these steps to resolve
the issue
please follow these steps to resolve the
issue have you updated your software
recently have you updated your software
recently I'll connect you with our
technical support
team I'll connect you with our technical
support team
let's reset your device and try
again let's reset your device and try
again can you tell me more about the
problem you're
experiencing can you tell me more about
the problem you're
experiencing we are already at our
topic upselling and cross selling this
is where you can use some of your sales
expertise with our English
phrases I noticed you might benefit from
our premium
service I noticed you might benefit from
service did you know we have a special
offer on English
lessons did you know we have a special
lessons you might also be interested
in you might also be interested
in we have a new feature that you might
like
we have a new feature that you might
like I'd recommend our English videos
for your
needs I'd recommend our English videos
needs we have a bundle deal that could
save you money
we have a bundle deal that could save
you
money would you like to upgrade to our
premium
package would you like to upgrade to our
package you might find our English
lessons
useful you might find our English
useful let me tell you about our latest
promotion let me tell you about our
latest
promotion have you heard about our new
English Master
Class have you heard about our new
Class coming up is our final to topic
end of call and followup and coming up
after that is my master class in
business English so make sure to stay
tuned is there anything else I can
assist you with
today is there anything else I can
today thank you for calling learning
English Pro have a great day
thank you for calling learning English
Pro have a great
day if you have any more questions feel
free to call us
back if you have any more questions feel
back I'm glad we could resolve your
issue today
I'm glad we could resolve your issue
today please don't hesitate to reach out
if you need further
assistance please don't hesitate to
reach out if you need further
assistance thank you for your patience
and understanding
thank you for your patience and
understanding have a wonderful day and
thank you for choosing learning English
Pro have a wonderful day and thank you
for choosing learning English
Pro I'll follow up with you to ensure
everything is
resolved I'll follow follow up with you
to ensure everything is
resolved we appreciate your business
thank
you we appreciate your business thank
you goodbye and thank you for calling
learning English
Pro goodbye and thank you for calling
learning English Pro
well done for sticking out throughout
the entire lesson and learning a hundred
new phrases for a call center I wish you
the very best in your future
employment welcome back to learning
English Pro this week we are covering
some essential business English this
video is perfect for anyone working in
business who wants to advance their
understanding of everyday English used
in the work environment
business English leaves behind slang and
Casual words for a more precise and some
might say sophisticated way to speak in
this lesson you will learn 10 essential
terms which will include adjectives
nouns verbs phrases and lots of examples
and definitions don't forget to check
out the extensive word list in the
description okay if you're ready sit
back relax and let's learn some business
English together let's get started with
our first word which is commercial now
commercial is an adjective and a noun
but we're going to take a look at the
adjective definition first as an
adjective commercial describes things
concerned with or engaged in Commerce or
things that make or are intended to make
a profit our first example sentence is
they have a commercial
agreement they have a commercial
agreement with this adjective it is
common to see the terms commercial
products or commercial property let's
move on and take a look at the noun
definition of commercial and it means a
television or radio
advertisement and our example sentence
is I saw the car on a TV
commercial I saw the car on a TV
commercial our next business term is
public relations
and this is a practice of understanding
the purpose of an organization and its
relationship within
Society we can also say it is the
planned and sustained activity of
Engagement between these two parties to
influence behavioral change and build
Mutual understanding and
Trust public relations is often
abbreviated to P or this is quite a
common term to use
we could say Rachel works in the public
relations
department or we could say Rachel works
in the P
Department p is a well-known
abbreviation in
English the public relations for the
company has been a
disaster the public relations for the
disaster the company has very good p
or the company has very good
PR our next term is
headquarters and this common noun means
the premises serving as the managerial
and administrative center of an
organization and just like public
relations this word can be abbreviated
to
HQ let's take a look at some synonyms we
can use for
headquarters head office and main office
are probably the two most common
synonyms used Base mission control and
nerve center are good too but they are a
little bit more military with their
Association let's take a look at our
example
sentence their headquarters are located
in
Paris their headquarters are located in
Paris okay it's time to move on to our
next word which is
agenda this common noun has a few
different meanings so let's run through
them our first definition of agenda is a
list of items to be discussed at a
formal meeting so it can be an actual
physical list we could say we have many
things on the agenda for today's
meeting our next definition of agenda is
a plan of things to be done or problems
to be addressed so it's more like a
General plan for the short to
medium-term Future our agenda for the
next few months is to hire some new
people and our final definition of
agenda is the underlying intentions or
motives of a particular person or group
and our final sentence example is his
agenda for the company seems to be very
reasonable so with this definition it's
more like a personal plan that someone
has for something if you have an agenda
you will need a strategy a strategy is a
plan of action designed to achieve a
long-term or overall
aim our sentence example is the
company's strategy is to reduce their
prices the company's strategy is to
reduce their
prices the verb form of this word is to
strategize meaning to devise a plan or
strategy we could say the p Department
strategized the New Media
campaign the PR department strategized
the New Media
campaign our next word is the common
noun penalty the definition of penalty
is a punishment imposed for breaking a
law rule or
contract the company received a penalty
from the tax
office the company received a penalty
office synonyms which are often used
instead of penalty are punishment
sanction or
fine related to this word we also have
the past participle penalized and this
means to be subject to a penalty or
punishment we have been penalized by the
government one more time we have been
penalized by the
government if you're enjoying this video
you should check out the other videos on
my channel relating to business English
money and banking the links for those
are on screen right now our next
business English term is the common noun
dress code this is a set of rules about
what clothing May and may not be worn in
a given setting like the workplace or
School some of the more common dress
codes include Formal Wear which includes
business attire and Suits a dress code
which is becoming more popular in the
modern workplace is smart casual this is
where you mix smart wear like shirts
with casual wear like jeans and some
workplaces will even have a casual dress
code this means that you can wear pretty
much anything that you like but there
are lots of different settings and lots
of different types of dress codes from
medical settings to school religion
construction and much much more moving
on our next business English term is the
common noun market research this
describes the action or activity of
gathering information about consumers
needs and
preferences our market research has
shown that most of our customers are
over 20 years of
age our market research has shown that
most of our customers are over 20 years
of age
we are conducting market research to
understand our customers
better we are conducting market research
to understand our customers
better let's move on and our next word
is a regular verb
authorize the definition is to give
official permission for or approval to
an
undertaking we could say I will
authorize the release of the
report I will authorize the release of
the
report or we could say Joan authorized
the payment last week Joan authorized
the payment last
week related to this word we also have
the common noun authorization this
involves the process of giving someone
permission to do or have
something we received the authorization
last
week we received the authorization last
week you may know our next word Branch
as relating to trees but we also have a
business English
definition our definition is a branch or
office of a large business or
organization operating locally or having
a particular function so think of a bank
having its headquarters in London and
then having lots of different branches
around around the world our sentence
example is the company director will
visit our branch in Dublin next
week the company director will visit our
branch in Dublin next week or we could
say do you have a branch in
Madrid do you have a branch in
Madrid in business English we also have
the phrase to Branch out and this means
to extend or expand one's activities or
interest in a new Direction our sentence
example is we intend to Branch out and
expand our range of products we intend
to Branch out and extend our range of
products if this is your first time
visiting my channel learning English Pro
you're very welcome to my channel my
name is j I'm narrating your lesson
today make sure to subscribe to my
channel for lots more fantastic English
learning content
[Music]
in today's lesson we're going to be
covering some essential vocabulary for
business English if you've seen any of
my lessons before you should know I go
very in depth on my vocabulary so by the
end of this video I'm really confident
you will know these words really really
well you're very welcome to your new
English vocabulary Channel learning
English Pro my name is jar I'll be
narrating your lesson
today let's take a look at our lesson
plan for this video and of course as
usual you'll be learning lots of key
vocabulary on our subject business
English and don't worry you will learn
lots of definitions and context in
relation to these new words plus I will
be giving you lots of sentence examples
so you can put your new vocabulary to
work straight away okay it's time to get
started so grab a pen and paper sit back
relax and let's learn some vocabulary
together our first word is
trademark repeat after me trademark
as a common noun a trademark refers to
an officially registered name symbol or
logo used to represent a product or a
firm trademark can also be used as a
regular verb and this simply means to
Mark something or register something as
a trademark and I'm sure you've seen
this symbol before TM this is the symbol
of a trademark so if this symbol is
beside a product name or a company name
you can be sure that it is trademarked
and protected by law are you ready for
your first sentence
example we have trademarks on five of
our product names and
services our next essential business
English word is
organize repeat after me
organize and this verb means to arrange
something systematically or make
arrangements or preparations for an
event or an
activity let's take a look at our
example
sentence I organized the training for
the new
employees there is a slight difference
in the spelling between British and
American English for this word organize
it's pronounced the same but organize in
American English has a zed and in
British English they have an S instead
let's take a look at another example
sentence but this time in the future
tense I will organize the meetings with
each manager for
you it's time to move on to our next
word
brand repeat after me
[Music]
brand brand is the term given to a
company's name and the recognizable
attributes that go with a company it's
about anything which defines its unique
identity you could say McDonald's is a
very recognizable
brand or how about Coca-Cola is an
international
brand another example sentence we could
say is the company's brand is directed
towards young professional
people our next word is a regular verb
expand repeat after me
expand it means to become or make
something larger or more
extensive our example
sentences their company will expand its
clothing range next
year let's take a look at a another
example sentence plans for the new
development have expanded by
50% and in this sentence we are using
the past participle form of this
verb our fifth word is
Clause repeat after me
clause and this word means a particular
condition or stipulation in a treaty
bill or
contract our sentence example is the
contract included a clause which
protects the employees
wages okay how about another sentence
example the company added a new Clause
to the contract which is very unfair up
next we have an English phrase null and
void repeat after me null and
void if an agreement a declaration or
contract is is null and void it is not
legally valid and is essentially canell
let's break down these two adjectives so
you can understand them a bit better
repeat after me
null null means that something that is
invalid or associated with the value of
zero or something lacking distinctive
qualities the other adjective was void
repeat after me void
and this means something that is not
legally binding or something that is
completely empty so null and void is
quite a negative phrase our example
sentences the contract will be null and
void if our client does not receive
payment
tomorrow our next business English word
is
competitor repeat after me
competitor a competitor is an
organization or country engaged in
commercial or economic competition with
others let's take a look at our example
sentence cocacola is a competitor of
Pepsi
Cola the local restaurant has a new
competitor up next we have a common noun
which is
invoice repeat after me
invoice the definition of invoice is a
list of goods sent or Services provided
with a statement of the sum due for
these it's like a bill or receipt really
our sentence example is we have received
an invoice from our printing
suppliers you can also use this word as
a verb we will invoice you for the
flower delivery from last
week can you believe we're almost at the
end of our lesson our ninth word is
counter
offer repeat after me counter
offer and this noun means an offer made
in response to
another let's take a look at our example
sentence we have received a counter
offer from Sha on the property in
Paris our final word for our lesson is
consensus repeat after me
consensus the noun consensus refers to
an idea or opinion that's been agreed on
by
[Music]
everyone Jamie and O were able to reach
a consensus on the
deal our final sentence example is there
was a growing consensus that Mary should
be the new
[Music]
manager that's great everybody that
brings us to the end of our lesson thank
you so much for watching I really
appreciate your
[Music]
support well here at learning English
Pro we have a fantastic video for you 10
business English words you need to know
in this video you will first see the
word and its definition followed by its
pronunciation and then you will hear
some conversation examples please note
we're just covering the business
definitions of these words today are you
ready to begin our first word is the
noun startup this term is used to
describe a brand new business typically
in its first few months or years of
trading
startup start up
our conversation example is Antonia is
working for a new startup in the web
design
industry our next word is forecast a
business forecast predicts various
aspects of a business's future movement
based on its current situation external
factors new products and plans for
marketing
forecast repeat after me
forecast and in our conversation example
we have the company's forecast for
profits for the coming year is very
favorable our next word is the noun
headquarters the definition is the
premise is serving as the managerial and
administrative center of an
organization
headquarters repeat after me
headquarters
our example in conversation is the new
headquarters will centralize the
company's
operations for our next term we have
something different an acronym
USP a USP is the unique selling
proposition of a company product or
service or what makes it different from
similar
offerings
USP USP P the USP of the food company is
that all its food is organic and locally
grown for our next and fifth term we
have the noun cold
call the definition is an unsolicited
visit or telephone call made by someone
trying to sell goods or
services now repeat after me cold call
cold
call our conversation example is the
sales team makes cold calls to potential
clients and tries to sell our products
our sixth word is the noun
recruitment recruitment is the process
of hiring new
employees
recruitment repeat after me recruitment
our example in conversation is our firm
specializes in the recruitment of nurses
for private hospitals our seventh word
is a noun
brand brand is the term given to a
company's distinctive name and the
recognizable characteristics that go
with that company to Define its unique
identity
brand brand
and our example in conversation is the
brands of some designers are easily
identifiable for our eighth term we have
the
phrase best practice this phrase
describes a generally acknowledged best
way of doing things in order to achieve
Optimum results here is your
pronunciation best
practice repeat after me best practice
in conversation we could say Chris is an
expert in best practice when it comes to
health and
safety for our penultimate business term
we have the adjective scalable if
something is scalable it means that it's
an idea that will work easily on a
larger scale to the one it currently
works
on scalable
repeat after me
scalable for our conversation example we
have Charlie's idea was great for the
company as it was scalable and offered
room to grow in the future our final
term for today's video is the noun
minutes now in relation to business it's
not related to time it's actually
related to a summarized record of the
proceedings at a
meeting minutes
repeat after me
minutes and here is our final
conversation
example Donal took the minutes for the
meeting with the senior
[Music]
Executives hey guys do you want to learn
business English it can be a really
tricky subject knowing what words to use
in what occas
but don't worry we have 10 business
English words you need to know from us
here at learning English Pro in this
video you will first hear the word with
its definition then practice
pronunciation with us before looking at
a conversation example please note all
definitions are business related our
first example is a noun commercial the
definition is a television or radio ad
advertisement
commercial
commercial and our example in
conversation is the company will run
their weight loss commercial on
television from
tomorrow our next business term is a
noun public
relations the professional maintenance
of a favorable Public Image by a company
or other organization or a famous person
and is often abbreviated to P
or public
relations public relations and our
conversation example is the new public
relations team have created a very good
image for the
brand our next word is another noun
headquarters and the definition is the
premises serving as the managerial and
administrative center of an organization
repeat after me
headquarters
headquarters and for our conversation
example we have the new headquarters
will centralize the company's
operations our next business word is
agenda this noun refers to a list of
things to be discussed or done at a
meeting conference or any type of
business
event
agenda repeat after me
agenda and our example in conversation
is they had a lot of topics to discuss
on the agenda for the
meeting our fifth word for this episode
is strategy and this relates to a plan
of action designed to achieve a
long-term or overall aim
strategy repeat after me
strategy and our example in conversation
is Ling and Amanda discussed their
strategy before they went to the meeting
coming up next we have the noun penalty
this refers to an official punishment
usually through a fine or other payment
for breaking a
contract repeat after me
penalty
penalty our example in conversation is
our team is very stressed due to the
recent penalty the company
received coming up next we have a phrase
dress
code the phrase dress code refers to a
set of company rules about what clothing
may or may not be worn at work dress
code repeat after me dress code our
example
is the dress code for the office is
smart
casual we have another
phrase market
research this refers to the research you
do to collect information about what
your customers need or prefer in a
certain product or service market
research
repeat after me market
research filamina conducts market
research with clients every few
weeks for our ninth term we are back to
nouns with authorization this word comes
from the verb to authorize which means
to give someone the legal or official
approval to do something authorization
refers to the approval itself
authorization
authorization our example in
conversation is Carla got the
authorization she needed for her
business
plan and for our last business English
term we have the noun
Branch the definition is a local office
or shop of a
company repeat after me branch
branch and our final conversation
example is we have opened a new branch
of our bank with amazing facilities for
our
customers that brings
[Music]
us hello you are very welcome to the
sixth part in our common English idiom
Series this episode will focus focus on
business
idioms our first idiom is back to square
one and this means to start something
over again because of a previous attempt
failed and our conversation example is
our first attempt failed so we are back
to square
one our next idiom is the big picture
and this means everything that is
involved with a particular
situation our example in conversation is
if we are going to succeed we need to
look at the big
picture next up we have Rock the Boat
this means to do or say something that
will upset people or cause
problems and our example in conversation
is when Peter tells Maria about the loss
of profits it will definitely rock the
boat so next up we have the elephant in
the
room this means an obvious problem or
controversial issue that no one wants to
discuss our example in conversation is
the office was uncomfortable today
because nobody wants to talk about the
elephant in the
room next up we have something that
sounds painful to twist someone's
arm this means to convince someone to do
something that he or she does does not
want to do our exampling conversation is
I'm going to have to twist Mary's arm
because I need her to work at the
weekend our next idiom is to take the
bull by the horns and this means to
directly confront a difficult situation
in A Brave and determined way our
example is we will have to tackle this
difficult situation and take the bull by
the horns
our final idiom for this episode is red
tape and this relates to official rules
and processes that seem excessive and
unnecessary and our final example is we
wanted to expand the business into the
property Market but there was too much
red tape involved
[Music]
hi welcome to this vocabulary lesson on
professions by learningenglish pro.com
let's
begin
architect
receptionist
receptionist businesswoman
businesswoman
secretary
businessman
businessman office
manager office manager
manager
CEO
CEO customer service
agent customer service
agent
programmer programmer
Banker
Banker stock
Trader stock
Trader insurance
[Music]
broker insurance
broker financial advisor
advisor financial
advisor
accountant
accountant bank
teller bank
teller
doctor doctor
surgeon
nurse
paramedic paramedic
radiologist
pharmacist
dentist
dentist optometrist
optometrist
chiropodist
[Music]
chiropractor
physiotherapist physiotherapist
construction
worker construction
worker police
woman police
man polican
FS
driver bus
driver
firefighter fire
fighter Market
Trader Market
Trader busker
bker
mailman
mailman Delivery
Man Delivery
Man taxi driver
Taxi
Driver
[Music]
farmer
Farmer
vet
Gardener gardener
[Music]
waiter
waitress
chef
chef host
Hostess
[Music]
Hostess in today's video I am responding
to a subscriber request May Mustafa
asked if I could make a video on crime
vocabulary and I am very happy to oblige
this is a huge complex field of English
which will involve not one or two videos
but probably an entirely new playlist so
thank you may Mustafa for the suggestion
there will be lots more on this topic in
future in this video I am focusing on
different types of crime and some
essential accompanying vocabulary if you
are affected by any of the issues
discussed in the video please reach out
to a trusted person like a friend or
doctor for advice and support and just
to note before we begin definitions in
this video are from the American
Judicial System although they are
commonly used in lots of different
countries as well our first term is the
crime of assault and bashery let's break
down these two different words to
understand what this crime
is an assault is an attempt or threat to
injure another
person and the word bashery means the
act of making contact with another the
person in a harmful or offensive
manner let's take a look at our first
example
sentence the police arrested him for
assault and battery against his
partner next up let's take a look at
this verb arrest and this means to seize
someone by legal Authority and take them
into
custody our next term is the crime of
aggravated assault
assault this is a more serious type of
assault and it is defined as an attempt
to cause serious bodily harm to an
individual with disregard for human life
factors that raise an assault to the
aggravated level typically include the
use of a weapon the status of the victim
the intent of the perpetrator and the
degree of injury caused let's take a
look at an example sentence he was
arrested for an aggravated assault in
the city center last
week our next term is another crime
aiding and abetting these two words are
synonyms of the word help and the
definition is a charge usually brought
against someone who helps in the
commission of a crime though legal
distinctions vary by state and Country a
person charged with these CRI crimes is
usually not present when the crime
itself is committed but they have
knowledge of the crime before or after
the fact and may assist in its
commission through advice actions or
financial support and we have a word to
describe someone charged with this crime
an accessory this describes someone who
gives assistance to the perpetrator of a
crime without taking part of
it our example sentences they were
arrested for being an accessory to the
crime next up we have the crime of
arson let's take a look at the
definition arson is defined as the
willful and malicious burning or Charing
of
property and while the majority of arson
crimes involve damage to buildings arson
can also be committed by a person who
sets fire to forests lands or boats
and we have the term arsonist to
describe a person who commits
arson now I'd like to take the time to
have a look at the verb to commit and in
relation to a crime it means to
perpetrate or carry out something like a
crime or even a sin so you don't make or
do a crime you commit a crime let's take
a look at some example
sentences she committed a crime
he has been arrested because he
committed
assault they committed arson in the
farest last summer he committed an
assault against his
brother next up we have the term
bribery let's take a look at the
definition bribery is the offer or
acceptance of anything of value in
exchange for influence on a government
or public official or employee our
example sentences he was arrested
because he committed
bribery if this is your first time
visiting my channel learning English Pro
you're very welcome my name is j and I'm
narrating your lesson today if you're
enjoying this lesson make sure to hit
the Subscribe button and stay updated on
all my latest videos let's get back to
our crime vocabulary and our next term
is the crime
burglary Burg
is typically defined as the unlawful
entry into almost any structure not just
a home or business with the intent to
commit any type of crime inside unlike
robbery which involves the use of force
or fear to optain another person's
property there is usually no victim
present during a burglary and we have
the word burglar to describe a person
who commits a
burglary let's move on to our next term
term which is the crime of cyber
bullying this crime refers to the use of
internet and or mobile technology to
harass intimidate or cause harm to
another person and we have the term
cyber bully to describe a person who
commits the crime of cyber
bullying let's move on to our next term
which is the crime of disorderly
conduct generally speaking police often
use a disorderly conduct charge to keep
the peace when a person is behaving in a
disruptive manner but presents no
serious public danger I want to take a
look at this important word
charge this word can be a verb or a noun
in in relation to crime and in the verb
form it means to officially accuse
someone of something especially an
offense under law and the noun describes
an accusation typically one formally
made against a prisoner brought to trial
let's take a look at some example
sentences the police charged him with
cyber
bullying the cops are charging
politicians with
bribery they will charge her with
committing a
burglary they charged the man with
assault and
bashery let's take a look at some
example sentence using charge as a
noun the charges against him are very
serious he received a charge of assault
this
morning another term which is related to
this is the phrasal verb to press
charges and when you press charges you
do it against someone
so the police do not make or give
charges they press charges against
someone let's take a look at some
example sentences the police have
pressed charges against the
singer the victim would not press
charges against the
attacker the police want to press
charges against the woman
okay let's move on to our next term
which is the crime of domestic
violence this refers to violent or
abusive acts committed by one family or
household member against
another domestic violence can refer to
physical harm or behavior that is
controlling coercive or threatening it
can occur in any kind of intimate
relationship married or unmarried
straight or gay
living together or simply
dating
[Music]
and hello and welcome back to learning
English Pro We are continuing our
exploration of English vocabulary
relating to Crime join me as I explore
lots of new English words relating to
types of crime the court and lots of
associated language if you're affected
by any of the issues raised in today's
video make sure to talk to a trusted
loved one or a professional like a
doctor okay let's get started and our
first term is fraud repeat after me
fraud fraud is the wrongful or criminal
deception intended to result in
financial or personal gain and one very
common type of fraud is credit or debit
card
fraud let let's take a look at the
definition credit and debit card fraud
is a form of identity theft that
involves an unauthorized taking of
another's credit card information for
the purpose of charging purchases to the
account or removing funds from it this
theft can occur physically when the
actual credit and debit card is taken or
the theft can occur when just the
numbers are stolen from an unprotected
website or a card reader at a gas
station an example sentence would be the
gang were involved in credit card
fraud the gang were involved in credit
card
fraud our next word is the noun
Court repeat after me
Court a court is any person or
institution often as a government
institution with the authority to
adjudicate legal disputes between
parties and carry out the administration
of justice in civil criminal and
administrative matters in accordance
with the rule of law the noun Court can
also describe the building or room where
a court
meets we also have the noun judge and a
judge is a public officer appointed to
decide cases in a law of Court you could
also say that the judge is the head of
the Court our next term is the crime of
criminal contempt of
court repeat after me Criminal contempt
of
court this crime refers to behavior
which disobeys offends or disrespects
The Authority or Dignity of a court it
can occur directly in the presidence of
the court or in indirectly when it
happens outside the presence of the
judge criminal contempt charges become
separate charges from the underlying
case we have the phrasal verb to hold in
contempt which is used in relation to
this crime let's take a look at some
examples of it in use a judge might say
I will hold you in contempt of court for
your
actions or we could say John was held in
contempt of court by the
judge up next we have another crime
disturbing the
peace disturbing the peace also known as
breach of the peace is a criminal
offense that occurs when a person
engages in some form of unruly public
Behavior such as fighting or causing
excessively loud noise an example
sentence would be he was arrested for
disturbing the peace
he was arrested for disturbing the
piece our next term is the crime of drug
possession it is a crime to willfully
possess illegal Controlled Substances
such as marijuana metamphetamine
cocaine LSD club drugs and
heroin these laws also criminalize the
possession of chemicals used in drug
cultivation and Manufacturing as well as
certain accessories related to drug use
we also have the crime of drug
trafficking drug trafficking is selling
transporting or importing illegal drugs
another name for this crime is drug
distribution when a state or federal
government classifies a substance as
controlled It generally means that the
use and distribution of the substance is
govern by law so controlled substances
is another word for illegal drugs or
prescription drugs next up we have the
crime of driving Under the Influence
this is also commonly known as a
DUI or drunk
driving Most states Define crimes of
driving Under the Influence as driving a
motor vehicle on a road or Highway while
under the influence of alcohol or drugs
an example sentence would be the actress
has two DUI
offenses the actress has two DUI
offenses up next we have the crime of
embezzlement repeat after me
embezzlement let's take a look at the
definition the crime of embezzlement is
where a person has lawful possessions of
the property of another converts or
takes that property for their own use
and has no intention of giving it back
this type of crime is most common in the
employment and corporate
fields we also have the term
embezzler repeat after me
embezzler this is a person who steals
money despite being entrusted to take
care of it so if you commit the crime of
embezzlement you are an
embezzler our next term is the crime of
extortion repeat after me
extortion extortion is the crime of
obtaining money or property by threat to
a victim's property or loved ones
intimidation or false claim of a right
we also have the crime of cyber
extortion and unfortunately this crime
is on the rise in modern society cyber
criminals use a tool known as ransomware
to encrypt a user's important files and
documents making them unreadable until a
ransom is paid next up let's explore the
difference between these two nouns jail
and prison which are often confused
jails are intended for short sentences
and temporary confinement while prisons
are are for felony sentencing longer
than a year jails are usually much
smaller than prisons and can be located
within a police station prisons are
usually huge complexes with many
buildings we also have the noun cell
which you can find in a jail or a prison
cell and the definition of this word is
a small room in which a prisoner is kept
confined in and to be more specific you
can refer to it as a prison cell or a
jail cell depending on which location it
is located let's also take a look at the
noun
prisoner this word describes a person
legally committed to prison as a
punishment for a crime or while awaiting
a trial let's take a look at some
synonyms for this word we have the word
inmate or convict and short for convict
we have the word con a more official
word would be
detain and a more casual or funny word
would be a
jailbird and jailbird brings us to the
end of our lesson let me know how you
got on with this lesson in the comments
below I'd love to hear from you
[Music]
and welcome back to learning English Pro
in this video we will be reviewing and
learning more English vocabulary about
the area of
crime also I have a trigger warning for
you I will be discussing some issues in
this lesson which are related to
violence so if you're sensitive to these
kind of issues please bear that in mind
okay let's get started with our first
term which is the crime of
forgery
forgery the crime of forgery generally
refers to the making of a fake document
the modification of an existing document
or the unauthorized signing of a
signature without
authorization someone who commits the
crime of forgery is known as a forger
this is defined as a person who produces
fraudulent copies or
imitations we can use the word forgery
along with fake or copy to describe a
forged document signature banknote or
work of
art let's move on to our next term which
is
harassment repeat after
me
harassment harassment refers to a broad
range of behaviors that are subject to
both criminal punishment and civil
liability there is a wide variety of
criminal laws forbidding harassment in
many forms including General harassment
crimes as well as specific forms of
harassment such as stalking and cyber
stalking a harasser is a person who
causes repeated emotional pain distress
or annoyance to another someone who is
the victim of harassment May seek a
restraining order this is a temporary
court order issued to prohibit an
individual from carrying out a
particular action especially approaching
or contacting a specified
person a type of harassment is stalking
which is a crime in
itself
stalking let's take a look at the
definition the crime of stalking can be
simply described as The Unwanted pursuit
of another person examples of this type
of behavior include following a person
appearing at a person's home or place of
business making harassing phone calls
leaving written messages or objects or
vandalizing a person's
property someone who commits this crime
is called a stalker and we Define this
as someone who harasses or persecute
someone with unwanted and obsessive
attention synonyms of stalker include
Prowler peeping Tom or Intruder our next
type of crime is is called a hate crime
repeat after me hate
crime a hate crime is the violence of
intolerance and bigotry intended to hurt
and intimidate someone because of their
race ethnicity national origin religion
sexual orientation or
disability this is also known as a bias
crime and it is a criminal offense where
the purveyors of hate can use explosives
arson weapons vandalism physical
violence and verbal threats of violence
to instill fear in their victims leaving
them vulnerable to more attacks and
feeling alienated helpless suspicious
and
fearful our next crime is
homicide repeat after me
homicide homicide is the killing of one
person by another but not all homicides
are crimes however all killings of
humans are included in the homicide
definition many homicides such as murder
and manslaughter violate criminal laws
others such as killing committed in
Justified self-defense are not criminal
illegal killings range from manslaughter
to murder with multiple degrees of each
representing the gravity of the the
crime let's take a look at these in
closer
detail there is first deegree
murder repeat after me first deegree
murder this is the most serious criminal
homicide typically first-degree murder
is both intentional and
premeditated premeditated means an
action which is thought of and planned
in
advance premeditated in regards to
murder can mean anything from a longtime
plan to kill the victim to a shorter
term plan the intent of the accused
murderer does not need to be focused on
the actual victim if someone planned on
killing one victim but by accident
killed someone else the murder is still
intentional and premeditated meaning a
first-degree murder
charge next up we have second degree
murder second degree murder
murder when there is a lack of
premeditation but the killer intended to
kill the homicide May draw second
deegree murder charges or perhaps
voluntary manslaughter
charges so moving on our next term is
manslaughter repeat after me
manslaughter this generally means an
illegal killing that falls short of
murder the lowest form of manslaughter
is involuntary manslaughter this means
that the perpetrator didn't intend to
kill anyone but still killed the victim
through behavior that was either
criminally negligent or reckless in
contrast voluntary manslaughter usually
means that the offender did not have a
prior intent to kill such as when the
homicide occurs in the heat of passion
and without
forethought and someone who Comm commits
a homicide is generally called a
murderer synonyms of murderer include
killer Slayer and
executioner if this is the first time
you're visiting my channel learning
English Pro you're very welcome my name
is j and I'm narrating your lesson today
make sure to subscribe and share this
video with a friend let's get back to
our vocabulary and our next crime is
identity theft repeat after me identity
theft identity theft and identity fraud
are terms used to refer to all types of
crimes in which someone wrongfully
obtains and uses another person's
personal data in some way that involves
fraud or deception typically for
economic gain someone who commits
identity theft or any kind of fraud is
generally known as a fraudster synonyms
of fraudster include scammer con artist
swindler my favorite which is gouger
chisler and
grifter our next crime is indecent
exposure repeat after me indecent
exposure indecent exposure laws in most
states make it a crime to purposefully
display one's genitals in public causing
others to be alarmed or offended
while the motive will vary from person
to person indecent exposure is often
committed for the sexual gratification
of the offender or to entice a sexual
response our next term is insurance
fraud insurance
fraud insurance fraud occurs most often
when an insured individual or entity
makes a false or exaggerated insurance
claim seeking compensation for injuries
or losses that weren't actually
suffered this type of crime can also be
committed upon customers through the
sale of unlicensed or bogus insurance
coverage to unsuspecting clients or an
insurance broker or agent's theft of
insurance premiums paid by
clients police and prosecutors typically
refer to a fraudulent Insurance claim as
either hard fraud or soft fraud hard
fraud is when someone deliberately fakes
an Accident Injury theft arson or other
loss to collect money illegally from
insurance companies soft fraud is when
normal honest people often tell Little
White Lies to their insurance company
for the purposes of filing or maximizing
a claim
[Music]
English Pro in this video we will be
reviewing and learning more English
vocabulary relating to Crime okay let's
get started our first term is the crime
of money laundering let's check out the
definition this is transferring money
derived from any criminal activity like
a bank robbery into seemingly legitimate
channels like a bank account or
investment money from a bank robbery is
considered dirty money so by putting
into a bank account you are making the
money clean again our next term is the
crime of
perjury to commit perjury is to
knowingly make misleading or false
statements under oath or to sign a legal
document you know to be false or
misleading this crime is taken very
seriously because the foundation of the
legal system depends on trust and
credibility if you commit this crime you
are called a perjurer and and we also
have an idiom to purger oneself to
purger is the verb form so we could say
John purered himself in court today and
moving right along our next term is
probation the definition of probation is
the release of an offender from
detention subject to a period of good
behavior under supervision so that
brings us to the crime of probation
violation this is an offense that occurs
when you break the terms or conditions
of your probation let's take a look at
the reasons why someone might violate
their
probation they might violate for not
appearing during a scheduled court
appearance on a set date and time or for
not reporting to your probation officer
at the scheduled time or place it could
be for visiting certain people or places
or traveling out of state without the
permission of your probation officer it
could also be for for possessing using
or selling illegal drugs or committing
other crimes or offenses or getting
arrested for another offense so if
you're on probation good behavior is
essential our next term is the crime of
public intoxication this is also called
public drunkenness and it occurs when a
person is visibly drunk or under the
influence of drugs in
public our next term is the crime of
racketeering this is when organized
groups run illegal businesses known as
rackets or when an organized crime ring
uses legitimate organizations to
embezzle
funds a lot of rackets deal in
industries that are clearly illegal such
as prostitution sex trafficking and drug
trafficking our next term is the crime
of rape this generally refers to
non-consensual sexual intercourse that
is committed by physical Force threat of
injury or other
dress the victim's lack of consent is
the crucial element a lack of consent
can include the victim's inability due
to the effects of drugs or alcohol to
say no we also have the term rapist to
describe someone who commits this
act there is also statutory rap
let's check out the definition this
refers to sexual relations involving
someone below the age of consent people
who are underage cannot legally consent
to having sex so any form of sexual
activity with them violates the law this
is true even in situations where they
signal their agreement rape and
statutory rape fall under the umbrella
term of sexual assault the definition
states that the term encompasses various
actions that involve Behavior or contact
toward another person without their
consent or permission let's take a look
at some of the actions that are covered
under sexual assault fondling kissing or
making unwanted bodily
contact forcing another person to
perform or receive oral sex forcing a
body part onto or into another person's
genitals and included in sexual assault
is forced masturbation if you have been
subjected to any of the issues covered
so far in this video please make sure to
talk to someone that you trust and can
offer you guidance and
support okay let's move on to our next
term which is the crime of
robbery robbery is theft accomplished by
violence or the threat of violence
unlike a theft or a burglary the crime
of robbery almost always requires the
presence of a victim who is threatened
with bodily
harm on screen you will see someone
committing a crime this is our next term
which is shoplifting and this generally
refers to the theft of merchandise from
a store or place of
business but did you know that many
states have enacted statutes
specifically authorizing stores and
their employees to detain suspected
shoplifters in certain
circumstances these laws serve to
protect the stores from lawsuits
claiming false imprisonment or false
arrest we also have the term
shoplifter the definition is a person
who steals goods from a shop while
pretending to be a customer we also have
some synonyms for
shoplifting like piling or pilage
there's also
purloining and filching let's move on to
our next term which is the crime of
solicitation
the definition is the crime of
solicitation is requesting encouraging
or demanding someone to engage in
criminal conduct with the intent to
facilitate or contribute to the
commission of that
crime commonly solicitation often is
linked to prostitution with the crime
being the request of someone to engage
in sex for money someone can still be
guilty of solicitation even if their
request is not accepted or the
subsequent crime simply never
happens and if you intentionally fail to
pay taxes or under report your taxable
income you could be charged with tax
evasion this is commonly charged against
those suspected of certain organized
crimes where the source of their income
is in doubt let's move on to our next
term which is the crime of telemarketing
fraud this crime happens when some some
sort of fraud is committed through
communication over the telephone this
can involve fraudulent selling to a
victim or some type of scam to steal
credit card or banking information or
private data such as identity
information let's roll on to our next
term which is the crime of
vandalism this is a broad Casher crime
that's used to describe a variety of
behaviors generally it includes any
willful Behavior aimed at destroying
altering or defacing property belonging
to another types of vandalism include
spray painting another's property with
the purpose of defacing or scratching
paint off someone's car breaking
someone's Windows defacing public
property with graffiti slashing
someone's
tires altering or knocking down street
signs
damaging someone's property in general
and it even includes throwing eggs at
someone's house or
car we also have the term Vandal to
describe someone who commits
vandalism and that brings us to the end
of our vocabulary lesson on crime I hope
you enjoyed it let me know how you got
on in the comments below I love to hear
for my subscribers and of course
hey everyone welcome back to learning
English Pro in this video we will be
exploring English vocabulary associated
with different types of Industry I will
be teaching you terminology used in
American English to describe and
categorize different types of Industries
okay if you're ready let's jump straight
into our lesson and our first industry
type is
construction this type of Industry
encompasses lots of different types of
companies and people who are involved in
construction this can range to apartment
and condominium construction home
builders Land Development indeed any
type of company involved in the building
and development of public buildings
homes or any type of construction are
included in this category and that
includes people like plumbers painters
and Carpenters
our next industry category groups three
different Industries together which are
all quite similar Arts entertainment and
Recreation this industry covers all the
kind of fun things that we like to do in
life from amusement parks bowling
centers golf courses museums and it also
includes musical groups and artists as
well as performers and creative artists
concerts and events by these types of
artist are also covered in this
industry gyms health and fitness clubs
also fall under this
category an industry which we all enjoy
is accommodation and food
services this industry covers tourism
and accommodation like a hotel a hostel
or a bed and breakfast and every type of
food service you can imagine from Street
vendors Food Service contractors curers
restaurants and coffee
shops next up we have the retail
trade companies who work in the retail
trade industry sell products directly to
the public in relatively small
quantities for use and
consumption and of course this industry
covers every type of shop or store you
can imagine from supermarkets to shoe
shops computer shops and everything in
between an industry which is directly
linked to the retail trade is the
wholesale trade
industry businesses which are included
in the wholesale trade are those which
sell Goods in large quantities and at
low prices typically to be sold on by
retailers for a
profit and all this stuff that we are
buying and selling moving around needs
an entire industry of its own
transportation and
warehousing and this industry covers the
transportation of people too so we have
companies such as Airlines and airports
as well as trains and delivery drivers
and trucks warehousing means the storage
of goods this can include warehouses of
course but it can also include different
companies that offer products such as
tank and refrigeration trucking and
storage so it's quite a varied
industry the manufacturing industry
covers businesses which make something
on a large scale typically with
Machinery it includes a vast multitude
of companies that produce every single
type of item that's available to us
today a lot of these manufacturers will
get their materials from the mining
industry
mining is the process or industry of
obtaining coal or other minerals from
the earth materials which are taken from
the earth include gold and silver coal
copper oil Sand and Stone another
industry which is dependent on the earth
is the agriculture forestry fishing and
hunting
industry this industry covers any type
of farming like crop farming or animal
farming and fish farming forestry covers
businesses which interact and use trees
to produce Timber and materials for
building and
Furniture businesses involved in hunting
typically provide wild animals for
food let's move on to a very different
type of Industry the real estate rental
and leasing industry this type of
Industry includes any type of business
involved in the selling or rental of
homes it also includes companies
involved in any type of renting such as
commercial leasing or even car rental or
costume
rental an industry which goes hand inand
with property is finance and
insurance this industry covers companies
such as Banks insurance companies
commodity dealers credit card issuers
and portfolio management any business
which engages with money in relation to
banking Investments or anything like
that is included in this category is
administration business support and
waste management this group of
Industries is comprised of companies
which support other services these
activities range from people like
secretarial workers people who clean
offices and other services like Pest
Control debt collection agencies
employment and recruitment agencies and
even security and waste disposal
services the next industry we will take
a look at is called
utilities utilities are essential
services that play a vital role in
economic and social development
companies that are involved in the
utilities industry Supply things like
water electricity natural gas and
provide sewage and sanitation although
utilities are private for profit
companies they are part of the public
service landscape providing as they do
such Staples for daily
living our next industry is Educational
Services Educational Services can be
explained as the training or
instructions given on different subjects
institutions giving these services on
different subjects can be training and
coaching centers colleges schools and
universities
I the next sector of Industry will'll
take a look at is the health care and
social assistance industry this is
comprised of establishments providing
health care and social assistance for
individuals the industry in this sector
include Physicians offices hospitals
medical laboratories nursing homes and
Youth and Family Service
Centers moving along to our next
industry which is called called the
professional scientific and Technical
Services industry this comprises of
companies and organizations which
specialize in performing professional
scientific and Technical activities for
others this industry includes
professionals such as accountants
advertisers Architects Engineers HR
consultants and lots of science related
jobs these activities require a high
degree of expertise and training
the information industry is comprised of
companies and organizations that are
information intensive in one way or the
other typically establishments are
engaged in the following processes such
as producing and distributing
information and cultural products
providing the means to transmit or
distribute these products as well as
data or Communications and processing
data
the final industry we will take a look
at is defined as the other services
sector this comprises of companies and
organizations which are engaged in
providing services not specifically
provided for elsewhere in the
classification
system establishments in this sector are
primarily engaged in activities such as
equipment and Machinery repairing
activities such as providing dry
cleaning and laundry services personal
care Services death care services and
pet care services this sector also
includes things like parking services
and even dating services so we could
definitely call this sector a
miscellaneous sector covering lots of
things that are hard to squeeze into
other classifications and industries and
that
[Music]
bring hi everyone I hope you are doing
well in this video we will be exploring
the different American Federal Holidays
that occur during a calendar year you
will learn their names and some
background information about each
holiday like the origins of the holiday
and what traditions are associated with
them so what exactly is a federal public
holiday federal holidays in the United
States are calendar dates that are
designated by the US government as
holidays on US federal holidays
non-essential federal government offices
are closed and federal government
employees are paid for the holiday
although not required as a general rule
other institutions such as Banks
businesses and schools and the stock
market may be closed on federal
holidays so what are the names of these
federal holidays let's take a look and
start in January and our first public
holiday is on the very first day of
January of the New Year it's New Year's
Day so what TR Traditions are associated
with this holiday festivities include a
countdown to midnight on the night
before which is called New Year's
Eve it is really common to have a New
Year's Eve party typically with your
friends and family and it's widely known
that the place to be on New Year's Eve
is Time Square in New
York it is here that you will see the
famous ball drop this is a large
decorated ball which drops down a pole
and when it hits the bottom it is
midnight and the start of a new
year another tradition associated with
this holiday time is a kiss you kiss the
person you love at midnight our next
federal holiday is also in January it's
called Martin Luther King Jr day it
falls on the third Monday in January and
it can also be referred to as MLK Day
the day of course honors the man of the
same name King was a prominent leader of
the civil rights movement and a Noble
Peace Prize laurat who was known for his
use of nonviolence and Civil
Disobedience King was fatally shot at
the Lorraine Motel in Memphis Tennessee
on April 4th
1968 and the first MLK day was held on
January the 20th
1986 moving on through the calendar year
next up it's
February the next federal holiday in the
calendar is called Washington's birthday
although it's better known as
President's Day and by Washington we're
referring to George Washington he was
the first president of the United States
of
America this federal holiday is
celebrated on the 3D Monday in February
it became a Federal holiday in
1885 these days it is seen as a
celebration of all presidents who have
served for the United States a food
which is associated with the holiday is
Cherry Pie this is based on a legend of
Washington in his youth chopping down a
cherry
tree for the months of March and April
we have no federal holidays we have to
wait until May for the next one which is
Memorial Day
this federal holiday is celebrated on
the last Monday in May this federal
holiday is a day for mourning US
military personnel who have died in
combat Memorial day has been celebrated
since
1868 many people visit cemeteries and
memorials on Memorial Day to honor and
mourn those who died while serving in
the US
military let's move on to to our next
federal holiday which is in June and one
which is also brand
new this new federal holiday is called
juneth so what is it all about this new
federal holiday celebrates the
emancipation of African-Americans from
slavery in the United States the
Emancipation happened in
1863 the 1 juneth will be held on June
19 2022 this marks the date in 1865 when
the US Army proclaimed freedom for
enslaved people in Texas which was the
last state of Confederacy with
institutional slavery juneth was made a
Federal holiday by President Joe Biden
in
2021 our next federal holiday is in July
and it's a quintessential American
holiday Independence Day which is
celebrated on the 4th of July this
Federal public holiday is typically
associated with big celebrations and
parties across the country this holiday
commemorates the Declaration of
Independence from
1776 and almost 100 years later in 1870
Congress first made this Day a federal
holiday so what do Americans get up to
on Independence Day they enjoy parades
fairs along with carnivals and different
types of Ceremonies and we can't forget
the classic American barbecue of sports
like baseball and of course
fireworks for our next public holiday
we'll have to skip the month of August
and move directly on to September it is
in this month that we have Labor Day
known as The Unofficial end of summer
this holiday is celebrated on the first
Monday in September so what is Labor Day
it honors and recognizes the American
labor movement it also honors the works
and contributions of laborers to the
development and success of the United
States of America the weekend which is
attached to this federal holiday is
known as Labor Day weekend this period
in September is well known throughout
the states for Labor Day sales in retail
let's roll on to our next federal
holiday which is in the month of
October the name of this holiday is
Columbus Day and it's held on the second
Monday in
October Columbus Day marks the
anniversary of Christopher Columbus's
arrival to the Americas on October 12th
1492 Columbus Day and how it came about
is associated with Italian Americans and
it became a Federal holiday in
1937 let's move on to November where we
we have two Federal public
holidays the first one on the calendar
is Veterans Day this is celebrated on
November the 11th it became a Federal
holiday in
1954 Veterans Day honors all veterans a
veteran is someone who has previously
fought for the American Army the next
federal holiday which is also in
November is
Thanksgiving this is celebrated on the
4th Thursday in November it was made a
national holiday by Congress in
1870 traditionally Thanksgiving is all
about giving thanks and celebrating the
Harvest a big part of Thanksgiving
Traditions is the family dinner but
Americans do like their parades and
Thanksgiving is known for them another
activity is watching sports and there's
always a big game on Thanksgiving daying
let's move on to our last month of the
year December and our final public
holiday which is Christmas Day Christmas
Day falls on December 25th and like
Thanksgiving it became a federal public
holiday in
1870 it is associated with the Christian
celebration of the birth of Christ
although it's celebrated by lots of
different religions and peoples it's
mainly Associated these days with gift
giving along on with the mythical figure
of Santa Claus and like Thanksgiving the
family dinner is a centerpiece of the
tradition those who are religious
typically attend church
celebrations this
[Music]
P hey there welcome back to learning
English Pro today we are diving into the
fascinating world of artificial
intelligence or AI if you're ready to
boost your English vocabulary while
learning about Cutting Edge technology
you're in the right place in this video
we'll explore essential AI terms that
will help you navigate this exciting
field an algorithm is a stepbystep
instructions or rules that a computer
follows to perform a specific task in
the context of AI algorithms play a
crucial role in data processing
decision- making and problem solving
they're like recipes for computers
guiding them through various processes
to achieve desired outcomes moving on to
our second term machine learning machine
learning is a subset of AI that involves
the use of algorithms and statistical
models to enable computers to learn from
data instead of being explicitly
programmed machines can improve their
performance over time by identifying
patterns and making predictions based on
the information they've
gathered term number three is neural
networks these are a fundamental Concept
in Ai and machine learning neuron
networks are computational models
inspired by the structure and
functioning of the human brain they
consist of interconnected nodes or
neurons that process and transmit
information neural networks are crucial
for tasks like image recognition and not
natural language
processing natural language processing
often abbreviated as NLP is a branch of
AI that focuses on enabling computers to
understand interpret and generate human
language NLP Technologies are used in
applications like chatbots language
translation sentiment analysis and text
summarization now let's explore deep
learning this is a specialized subset of
machine learning that involves complex
neural networks with multiple layers
these deep neural networks can
automatically learn to represent data in
more abstract and hierarchical ways this
can lead to incredibly accurate results
in tasks like image and speech
recognition as well as language
generation our final term for today is
data mining this involves the process of
discovering patterns Trends and useful
information from large sets of data in
the context of AI data mining plays a
crucial role in extracting insights that
can be used to improve algorithms make
predictions and enhanced decision-making
and there you have it six essential AI
terms that will give you a solid
foundation for understanding the
fascinating world of artificial
intelligence remember to
hello dear viewers and welcome back to
learning English Pro in this video we'll
be diving into the world of home office
vocabulary whether you're new to this
topic or simply want to expand your
English vocabulary stick around because
I've got a comprehensive list of
essential words and phrases to help you
communicate effectively in your home
works space so we're going to turn this
boring room into a home office and let's
start with the basics your desk is the
heart of your home
office and your chair is your trusty
companion as you
work you might also have a comfortable
chair mat to protect your floor and
don't forget the shelves for additional
storage now let's talk about your
computer setup your computer or laptop
is your gateway to the digital world
the monitor is your screen the
keyboard and mouse are your tools for
navigating and a webcam for virtual
meetings is a must these
days keeping your home office organized
is crucial you'll need a filing cabinet
for important
documents you'll also need folders for
organizing and stationary like paper
pens and
pencils don't forget the stapler for
putting together those important
reports make sure to stay connected with
a phone for calls and messages and a
Wi-Fi rouer for internet
access you might also need headphones
for private
calls and a calculator is great for
quick calculations
ensure good lighting with a desk lamp
now it's time to think about the
Aesthetics of your home office let's add
some
plants these are great to look at and
help purify the air around you and stay
relaxed with some nice photographs and
pictures you can personalize the space
more with art and stylish
touches let's get back to a little bit
of technology a printer or scanner can
be handy for
paperwork a whiteboard is great for
important
reminders keep your space tidy with a
waste basket or trash can for disposing
of
rubbish and finally the most important
thing to add is
you and there you have it a
comprehensive list of home office
vocabulary in English
this will help you to build and navigate
your ideal home workspace don't forget
to
[Music]
check hello and welcome back to learning
English Pro my name is j your online
chure and guide in today's lesson we are
taking a tour of money and finance
English vocabulary in a master class
from learning English Pro in this lesson
you'll transfer form your English skills
through a series of engaging and
informative lessons on financial
terminology and Concepts so whether
you're starting out or looking to refine
your expertise this master class has
something for everyone in our first
lesson we're going to take a look at
some basic money vocabulary so get ready
for lots of useful English learning and
don't forget to
subscribe money is at the center of
almost every aspect of Our Lives
in English we say money makes the world
go
round another word for money you may
hear is cash and this usually refers to
physical money you might hear someone
say I have some cash in my pocket cash
can also refer to small amounts of
non-physical money you could hear
someone ask can you transfer some cash
to my bank account please physical cash
money comes in two different forms coin
and Bank
notes however becoming more common is
credit cards and debit
cards we will take a look at debit cards
later but for now I want to focus on
this important word credit the
definition of credit is the ability of a
customer to obtain goods or services
before payment based on the trust that
payment will be made in the future
another way to talk about credit is to
say that it is money that you borrow and
are usually charged interest on but what
is
interest interest is the charge for the
privilege of borrowing money the amount
of Interest charged is usually called
the interest
rate something which you are commonly
charged interest on is called a loan a
loan is a sum of money that is expected
to be paid back with interest
interest let's use some of these words
in a
sentence we needed some credit so we got
a loan from the bank with a good
interest
rate so what kind of loans can you take
out from the bank let's have a little
look at three types of loans you may
commonly take out in your lifetime when
you need a loan to buy a house we call
this loan a mortgage
the t is silent
mortgage another common loan is a
student
[Music]
loan and many people get a car loan to
purchase a new
car when people have a lot of money we
have certain words we use to describe
them like
wealthy or Rich
or you can say someone is very well
off when you have lots of money you can
buy lots of expensive things and in
English we say that the wealthy have
comfortable
lives but we all need to ask can money
buy you
happiness if you don't have a lot of
money you might be described as poor or
broke or someone might say that you are
badly
off people who don't have much money
might have to live on a budget and they
may have stressful lives which can
affect health and
well-being okay let's move on and have a
look at some new different words for
money and how we may use
them a word I'm sure everyone around the
world knows very well tax and this is
the money that you pay to the government
and you pay it on Goods services profits
and income our next word is
donation and this word describes money
you give to
charity next up we have two words salary
or wages and these words mean money paid
to you from your employer it is usually
paid weekly or monthly and if you work
hard you may get a
bonus this is an additional payment from
an employer for good performance
and in Western culture it is quite
common for your employer to give you a
Christmas
bonus let's move on and have a look at
some words for money you may use when
you're
shopping our first word describes
something you may find typically in a
magazine or a newspaper a
coupon a coupon is a token entitling the
holder to a discount off a particular
product something you can give as a
present to someone is a voucher or a
gift certificate this usually comes as a
piece of paper or an electronic card
that entitles the holder to a cash
discount or it may be exchanged for
goods or
services when you go to a restaurant and
you have a nice experience with the
serving staff you can leave them a tip
this is a sum of money given to someone
as a reward for a
service it has become more and more
common to pay by card we have already
taken a look at credit but let's have a
look at a debit card and what that
means a debit card is a card allowing
the holder to spend or use money
directly from their personal bank
account when you use a card to pay for
something you might need to use your
chip and pin this is a way of paying for
goods by debit or credit card whereby
one enters one's personal identification
number into an electronic
device another way which is becoming
very common is tap and pay this is a
form of payment that allows a customer
to top a card or device against a card
reader to pay instead of inserting a
card and by device we usually mean a
phone or maybe even a watch can you
believe that brings us to the end of our
vocabulary lesson
[Music]
I hello I hope you're having a great day
you're very welcome to this English
vocabulary lesson on banking so if
you're ready sit back relax and let's
learn some English together the first
word we will look at today is of course
Bank it is a verb and a noun but we will
take a look at the noun definition first
a bank is a financial institution it
uses money deposited by customers for
investment it pays out money when
required it makes loans at interest and
it exchanges currency let's move on and
take a look at the verb definition of
bank as a verb it means to have an
account at a particular bank so you
could say she banks with the National
Bank sometimes a bank will have more
than one office or store an office of a
bank is called a branch and the full
definition of a branch is a division or
an office of a large business or
organization operating locally or having
a particular function let's use this
word in a sentence
example the bank has a branch in the
village the bank has a branch in the
village when you open a bank account you
become a customer of the the
bank let's take a closer look at this
term bank account the definition is a
record or statement of financial
deposits and
expenditure let's look at some sentence
examples you could say I need a bank
account but it is better English to say
I need to open a bank account we use the
verb open when we want to create or have
a bank account so when you go to the
bank you could say hi I would like to
open a bank account please let's take a
look at the things you need to open a
bank account you will need official
identification like a passport or
national ID you will also need proof of
address like an electricity bill and you
will have to fill out an application
form once you have completed your
application and you get your bank
account one of the first things you will
receive is a debit card
if you want to learn more about debit
cards and different types of money check
out my money vocabulary video the link
is on screen now one of the first places
you will use your debit card is probably
the
ATM now what does ATM mean it is an
acronym of automated teller machine at
the ATM you will also need your pin pin
is another acronym and it stands for
personal identification number a verb
withdraw which means to take money out
of an account so you could say I
withdraw about $80 a week from my
account another way we can say this is
by using the phrasal verb take out I
need to take out some money from the ATM
let's move on to our next word which is
the opposite of withdrawal
lodgment and this noun means the action
of ping money into your bank
account let's use it in a sentence
example hello I would like to make a
lodgment please this is something that
you can say at the desk in the
bank and of course we have a verb for
this action as well Lodge and this verb
describes of course the act of putting
the money into your bank account a
sentence example is I will Lodge the
money into my bank account tomorrow
we can also use a phrasal verb here put
into I put some money into my account
yesterday coming up next I have a
question for you how much money do you
have to answer this question you will
need to know what the word balance means
in financial terms this noun means the
amount of money held in a bank account
so to know your balance you could say I
should check my balance leisure
if you don't have very much money you
could say my bank balance is very low or
if you have lots of money a nice way to
say it is my account balance is pretty
healthy there are so many banking terms
that I couldn't fit them all into this
video so I've decided to make another
video on banking terms our first banking
term is credit
transfer and this is a direct payment of
money from One bank account to
another let's take a look at an example
conversation can you send me the money
by credit
transfer and the reply could be I will
transfer the money to your account
straight
away our next banking term also involves
money leaving your account direct debit
and the definition is an arrangement
made with the bank that allows a third
party to transfer money from a person's
account on agreed dates typically in
order to pay
bills let's take a look at an example
sentence I pay my phone bill by direct
debit every
month one more time I pay my phone bill
by direct debit every month our next
banking term is standing order and this
is an instruction to a bank by an
account holder to make regular fixed
payments to a particular person or
organization you could say I organized a
standing order with my bank to pay my
rent every
month next up I have a question for you
what are Bank
charges not
sure well to make a profit and pay
operating expenses Banks typically
charge for the services they provide
let's take a closer look at this word
charge which is a noun and the
definition is a price asked for goods or
services a sentence example is I get a
lot of Bank charges on my
account something you may receive a bank
charge on is an
overdraft this is a shortfall in a bank
account caused by drawing more money
than the account holds
when you are low on money in your
account some banks will allow you to
spend more money than you
have when you have a balance of less
than zero we call this a minus
amount a sentence example could
be I have an overdraft on my account at
the
moment or we could use the adjective
overdrawn I am overdrawn on my bank
account at the
moment something else you can say is I
paid off my overdraft last week here we
are using the phrasal verb paid off and
in relation to banking paid off means
the act of giving a bank or a person all
the money that you owe them something
else you could pay off is a loan a loan
is a thing that is borrowed especially a
sum of money that is expected to be paid
back with
interest a sentence example is I got a
loan from the bank so I could go on a
dream
vacation we can also use the verb to
borrow I borrowed some money from the
bank so I could go on
vacation with bank accounts there are
generally two different types a savings
account or a checking account a checking
account is what they call it in America
and in British English it is called a
current
account let's take a closer look at a
savings account the definition is a bank
account where you save your money you
could also say that savings accounts are
designed for earning interest on your
money now I've just mentioned three
important words savings save and
interest so let's take a closer look at
save first and we'll come back to the
other two save is a verb and it means to
keep and store store up something
especially money for future
use in a sentence example we could say I
save my money in my savings account
every
month let's move on to our next word
which is saving this is the Geren or
present participle tense of the verb
save as an example we could say I am
saving my
money we also have a very similar word
which is a noun savings and this plural
noun means the money one has saved
especially through a bank or official
scheme you could say I keep my savings
in my bank
account the next word we're going to
look at is interest so what is
interest let's take a look at the
definition interest is Money Paid
regularly at a particular rate for the
use of money given as a loan or
credit there are two ways to think about
interest it is money the bank will
charge you on a loan or on an
overdraft but it is also what we call
the money the bank will pay you on
savings and Investments so one person
may say my bank charged me a lot of
interest on my
overdraft while another may say I earned
some money from the interest on my
savings can you believe that brings us
to the end end of another vocabulary
[Music]
lesson welcome back to learning English
Pro in this video we are back with more
financial English this time with a focus
on credit cards and an extensive and
detailed English glossery on common
terms and vocabulary associated with
billing interest rates and using a
credit card so if you're ready it's time
to sit back relax and let's learn some
English together our first term is card
holder card
holder let's take a look at the
definition a card holder is a person who
has a credit card or debit
card let's use it in an example sentence
I am a card holder and it is okay to
charge my card for this
purchase our next term is annual
fee repeat after me annual
fee this is a once yearly charge for
having a credit
card let's use this term in our example
sentence my annual fee for my credit
card is now
due up next we have transaction
fees transaction
fees the definition is a fee charged for
using a credit card for certain types of
transactions like in an
ATM we could say my bank does not charge
me any transaction
fees our next word is
balance
balance and in relation to a credit card
a balance is the amount of money you owe
on your credit card bill it can change
from month to month depending on whether
you pay your bill in full and on
time our example sentence is thankfully
the balance on my credit card is low at
the
moment if you have a high balance on
your credit card you may want a balance
transfer repeat after me balance
transfer this is a transfer of debt from
One credit card to another and you
usually do this for a fee our example
sentence is I need a balance transfer to
get my debt under
control up next we have the term credit
limit repeat after me credit
limit this is the maximum amount of
credit a borrower can use on a credit
card exceeding the limit usually
involves a penalty
fee we could say I cannot buy those
shoes because I have reached my credit
limit our next term is interest rate
which we've already mentioned in this
video interest
rate the definition is the charge for
borrowing a sum of money usually
expressed as a percentage of the
original loan charged annually remember
credit cards are a type of loan an
example sentence is the interest rate on
my bank's credit card is very
good one type of interest rate is the
annual percentage rate commonly known as
the AP or a
or the definition is a calculation of
the overall cost of your loan it is
expressed as an annual rate that
represents the actual yearly cost of the
funds borrowed it takes into account all
the costs during the term of the loan
including any set of charges and the
interest
rate we could say the APR on my credit
card is incredibly High I need a Balan
transfer to a new card to save
money we also have the term introductory
APR introductory
a and this is a lower interest rate
offered on a new credit card usually
during the first 6 months after the
introductory period the interest rate
increases an example sentence is I was
offered a very good introductory APR on
this new credit
card we also have a type of interest
rate called a fixed
rate fixed
rate this is described as an interest
rate that does not vary during the life
of a
loan let's take a look at our example
sentence the fixed rate of interest on
my credit card will expire at the end of
the
month let's move on to our next term
which is is prime
rate prime
rate this is defined as the rate of
interest that Banks charge their most
favored customers usually around
3% my bank must think I am a good
customer because they offered me the
prime rate on a new credit
card another type of interest rate is a
variable
rate variable
rate this is an interest rate that
changes based on the moves of another
rate index usually the prime
rate we could say my credit card comes
with a variable
rate our next English word is the verb
to
default
default the definition is the failure to
pay a
debt our example senten is I defaulted
on my credit card payments and now I am
in some financial
trouble and you know if you are
experiencing difficult with credit card
debt please seek advice from a
professional and trusted debt advice
organization lots of governments around
the world offer services to assist
people in financial trouble it can also
be a good idea to talk to your bank our
next term is default rate
default
rate this is defined as a particular
interest rate charged when a consumer
defaults on a credit agreement usually
much higher than the normal rate our
example sentence is the default rate on
my credit card is very
high next up we have minimum monthly
payment minimum monthly payment
and this is the smallest amount of money
a borrower can pay monthly towards their
credit card usually 2% of the balance we
could say my minimum monthly payment is
quite
high if this is the first time you're
visiting my channel learning English Pro
you're very welcome my name is j and I'm
narrating your lesson today make sure to
subscribe to get updated on all my
latest videos our next term is is late
fee repeat after me late
fee and our definition is a fee charge
for paying the minimum balance of a
credit card after the due date our
example sentence is I forgot to pay my
credit card bill and I got a late
fee let's move on to our next term which
is Grace
Period grace period
this is defined as a period of time when
no interest is charged on a credit
card our example sentence is with my new
credit card I have a grace period of 6
[Music]
months next up we have billing
cycle billing
cycle a billing cycle is the amount of
time between the last statement closing
date and the next billing Cycles must be
at least 21 days we could say the
billing cycle for my credit card seems
to come around very
quickly next up we have the term cash
advance repeat after me cash advance
when you withdraw money from your credit
card account it is known as a cash
advance card issuers typically limit the
amount of money you can withdraw to a
portion of your total credit limit and
charge High interest rates and fees on
the withdrawal making cash advances
costly I use my credit card at the ATM
and got a cash
advance and that brings us to the end of
our lesson on credit card English
[Music]
vocabulary in this video you will learn
about different types of insurance in
English Okay it's time to begin our
lesson and first up let's ask what is
insurance or how do we Define
insurance we could say insurance is a
way to protect oneself or an
organization from Financial
loss we could also say that insurance is
a type of risk management insurance is
generally provided by an insurance
company or an insurance broker and we
could call either of these types of
entities an
insurer one of the first types of
insurance many people get is car
insurance this can also be called motor
insurance in American English it can be
referred to sometimes as vehicle
insurance
another common type of insurance is
medical
insurance there are a few synonyms for
medical insurance like health
insurance it can simply be called
healthc
care or a health
plan another popular type of medical
insurance is dental insurance
sometimes this will be covered under a
health care
plan okay let's move on to a different
type of insurance home
insurance this may also be called
property
insurance home or property insurance
generally covers costs relating to
fire
T and costs incurred by weather damage
there are are also many subtypes of
property insurance such as boiler
Insurance earthquake
insurance flood
insurance there is also landlord
insurance and renters insurance and we
have Windstorm Insurance which covers
damage from hurricanes and
tornadoes another way to protect your
home if you have a mortgage is mortgage
protection this type of insurance is
designed to pay off your mortgage if you
were to pass away and some mortgage
protection policies will cover mortgage
payments if you become disabled or
sick a very important insurance for a
lot of people is pet insurance this type
of insurance policy is purchased by pet
owners to offset the overall cost of
their animals medical
bills let's move on to a different type
of insurance income protection
income protection insurance pays part of
your lost income if you're unable to
work because of disability caused by an
illness or injury a subtype of income
protection is disability insurance or
long-term disability
insurance our next type of insurance is
liability insurance this term refers to
an insurance product that provides an
insured party with protection against CL
claims resulting from injuries and
damage to other people or property a
common type of liability insurance is
public liability this covers the cost of
claims made by members of the public for
incidents that occur in connection with
business
activities professional liability
insurance is insurance that protects
professionals such as accountants
lawyers and Physicians against
negligence and other claims initi Creed
by their
clients up next we have life insurance
this type of insurance generally
provides an income to an insured
person's family upon their death funds
can be used for burial funeral and other
final
expenses and that brings us to the end
of this English lesson on types of
insurance don't forget about
hello there English Learners welcome
back to learning English Pro today we're
diving into an essential topic for
anyone planning to rent in the USA
renting a play can be exciting and
sometimes a challenging experience
especially when it comes to
understanding the terminology in this
video we'll explore 15 key terms and
words that will help you navigate The
Rental process with
confidence so let's get started and
first up we have the lease agreement
this is a legal doc document that
outlines the terms and conditions of the
rental Arrangement between you and your
landlord it includes details such as the
rent amount lease duration and the rules
for the
property next we have the security
deposit this is a sum of money you pay
upfront to the landlord as a security
against any potential damages to the
property it's refundable at the end of
your lease if the property is in good
condition
when you're interested in a rental
you'll likely need to fill out a rental
application this form provides
information about you your income and
references which helps the landlord
assess your eligibility as a
tenant utilities are essential services
like water electricity and gas it's
important to clarify whether these are
included in your rent or if you be
responsible for paying for them
separately a tenant is the person who
rents and occupies the property that's
you remember as a tenant you have rights
and responsibilities outlined in the
lease
agreement your landlord is the property
owner who is renting out the place to
you they're responsible for maintaining
the property and addressing any issues
that arise during your
lease the rent due date is the day each
month when your rent payment is due make
sure to pay on time to maintain a good
relationship with your
landlord if something in your rental
needs fixing you can submit a
maintenance request to your landlord and
they'll arrange for repairs to be
made subletting is when a tenant rents
out their rented space to another person
however this usually requires permission
from the
landlord eviction is the legal process
of removing a tenant from a property it
usually happens when a tenant doesn't
follow the terms of the
lease when you move into a new place
it's wise to conduct a move in
inspection this involves noting down any
existing damages or issues in the proper
property to avoid disputes
later as your lease term ends you might
have the option for a lease renewal this
allows you to extend your lease for
another period often with updated
terms before bringing a furry friend
along check the pet policy this outlines
whether pets are allowed any
restrictions and potential fees
the term amenities describes extra
features or facilities that a rental
property might offer such as a gym a
pool or a laundry
room last but not least consider getting
renters insurance this coverage protects
your personal belongings in case of
theft damage or other unexpected
events so there you have it these are
some of the key terms and words that
will be incredibly useful as you
navigate the world of renting in the USA
remember these terms will help you
communicate effectively with landlords
and make informed decisions English Pro
today we're delving into the world of
Investments where we will break down
different types of Investments and
explore the relevant vocabulary
associated with each and let's begin
with stock market Investments a stock
market in brief is a centralized Market
place where stocks are bought and sold
by investors stocks also known as
equities or shares represent ownership
in a corporation or company when you own
a stock you essentially own a portion of
that company companies issue stocks to
raise capital for various purposes such
as expanding their operations investing
in new projects or reducing debt
Dividends are payments made by a
corporation to its shareholders at out
of its profits or retained earnings
these payments are typically distributed
regularly often on a quarterly basis as
a way for the company to share its
financial success with its
investors and a portfolio is the
collection of stocks and securities
owned by an
investor let's move on to bond
Investments which are known for their
stability here are some relevant
terms bonds are debt Securities this is
where an investor loans money to an
entity in exchange for periodic interest
payments and the return of the Bond's
face value at
maturity the coupon rate is the interest
rate that a bond pays annually and the
maturity date is the date when a Bond's
principle is due to be
repaid now let's take a look at a
category that encompasses both stocks
and bonds Securities these are are
financial instruments representing
ownership or financial interests in
various entities they play a crucial
role in investment markets offering a
wide range of opportunities for
investors real estate Investments
involve properties where you buy
properties in order to generate
additional income or Capital the term
real estate means land and any property
attached to it a common way to gain
income from real estate Investments is
rental income this is money earned by
leasing or renting out your investment
properties property management is an
important aspect of real estate
investment and it relates to the
administration operation and oversight
of real estate properties on behalf of
property owners or investors it involves
a wide range of responsibilities aimed
at maintaining and maximizing the value
of real estate
assets let's move on to mutual funds
mutual funds pull money from various
investors to buy a diversified
portfolio key terms include nav or net
asset value this is the per share market
value of a mutual fund the expense ratio
is the cost of managing a mutual fund
expressed as a percentage of assets
under management in relation to
Investments diversification means
spreading Investments across various
assets to reduce your risk our fifth
type of investment is Commodities
investment commodities are tangible
goods that can be bought or sold here
are some terms related to this type of
Investments which Goods can we consider
Commodities well Commodities can be raw
materials or primary agricultural
products that can be bought and sold
such as gold oil wheat art wine you name
it there are lots of different types of
Commodities in that market an essential
term of the Commodities Investments
Market is future contracts these are
agreements to buy or sell a commodity at
a specified future date and price and
the spot price is the current market
price for immediate delivery of a
commodity an investment type which is
always a Hot Topic is cryptocurrency
Investments these are digital or virtual
currencies that use cryptography for
security here are some essential terms
Bitcoin was the very first
cryptocurrency and it is the most
well-known often referred to as digital
gold a crucial term for understanding
cryptocurrency is the blockchain this is
a distributed Ledger technology that
undery most
cryptocurrencies and if you have
cryptocurrency you're going to need a
wallet this is a digital tool for
storing sending and receiving
cryptocurrencies moving along to private
Equity
Investments private Equity involves
investing in privately held
companies and the investment management
company that invests in private
companies is known as a private Equity
Firm venture capital is the funding
provided to Startup and small businesses
in exch exchange for equity and if you
remember from earlier an equity equals
the share in the company a leverage
buyout or an lbo is the acquisition of a
company using significant amount of
borrowed
funds our final investment type is a
hedge fund investment hedge funds are
investment funds that employ various
strategies to generate returns Alpha is
a measure of an investment's return Rel
ative to its risk Short Selling is the
practice of selling borrowed assets with
the hope of buying them back at a lower
price our final term is high frequency
trading or
hft this is a trading strategy that uses
Advanced algorithms for Rapid buying and
selling of
assets and that concludes our
exploration of investment vocabulary
[Music]
hello and welcome back to learning
English Pro in this lesson we're going
to take a look at vocabulary and
terminology relating to economics you'll
learn 15 fundamental economic terms that
will help you grasp the complexities of
the financial world and our first term
is supply and
demand these are fundamental forces that
dictate the prices of goods and services
in a market supply refers to the
quantity available while demand rep
represents how much people want it
prices rise when demand exceeds Supply
and prices fall when Supply exceeds
demand let's move on to our next
term
inflation inflation is the increase in
the general price level of goods and
services over time resulting in the loss
of purchasing power for a
currency it's measured by the Consumer
Price Index or the CPI which we'll get
into later the opposite of inflation is
deflation this is where prices decrease
over time it can lead to reduced
consumer spending and economic
stagnation gross domestic product or GDP
measures the economic performance of a
country it's the total value of all
goods and services produced within a
nation's borders in a given time period
a related term is GDP per
capita this is the average income of a
country's citizens and is calculated by
dividing the GDP by the population it
reflects the standard of living in a
nation let's move on to our next term
fiscal policy this involves government
actions concerning Taxation and
expenditure to influence the economy
governments use fiscal policy to
stabilize economic growth control
inflation and reduce
unemployment another type of policy you
may hear about in economics is monetary
policy this is the management of the
money supply and interest rates by a
central bank it plays a crucial role in
controlling inflation and maintaining
economic stability
a recession is a significant decline in
economic activity often marked by
reduced consumer spending business
Investments and high unemployment
rates a budget deficit happens when a
government spends more money than it
collects in taxes it's usually funded by
borrowing leading to national
debt a trade balance refers to the
difference between a country's exports
and imports a trade surplus happens when
a country exports more than it Imports
while a trade deficit is the
opposite let's move on to look at
different types of
economies a market economy is where
prices are determined by supply and
demand and private individuals and
businesses make most of the economic
decisions
a mixed economy combines elements of
both free market capitalism and
government intervention governments
regulate certain industries and provide
essential
services our next term is opportunity
cost this is the value of the next best
alternative that must be forgot when a
decision is made to allocate resources
to one option instead of
another the Consumer Price Index or CPI
measures changes in the cost of a basket
of goods and services over time it's
used to gauge inflation and cost of
living
[Music]
adjustments our final term is
entrepreneurship this involves
identifying business opportunities
organizing resources and taking risks to
create and operate successful
Enterprises English Pro today we're
diving into the world of stock market
Investments and expanding your financial
vocabulary so whether you're an aspiring
investor or simply curious about stock
market this video is for
you let's cover the basics stock markets
are essential platforms where investors
buy and sell ownership in companies they
help businesses raise Capital provide
liquidity for investors and set stock
prices based on supply and
demand these markets offer diverse
investment opportunities and act as
economic
indicators examples of stock exchanges
include the New York Stock Exchange the
NASDAQ the London Stock Exchange and
Tokyo Stock Exchange
another fundamental term of stock market
Investments is shares also known as
stocks these are units of ownership in a
company when you own shares of a
company's stock you own a portion of
that company and your ownership entitles
you to a share of its profits and a say
in certain corporate
decisions if you own shares or stocks in
a company you are known as a shareholder
in that
company Dividends are payments made by a
company to its shareholders as a reward
for owning its stock these payments come
from the company's profits and are
typically distributed regularly
providing shareholders with a portion of
the company's
earnings our next term is bull market a
bull market is a period in the financial
markets characterized by Rising stock
prices optimism amongst investors and
overall confidence in the economy it's a
time when Investments tend to perform
well and there is a general belief that
the upward Trend will
[Music]
continue the opposite of a bull market
is a bare Market it's a period in the
financial markets characterized by
declining stock prices pessimism amongst
investors and a lack of confidence in
the economy during a bare Market
Investments tend to not perform very
well and there is a belief that the
downward Trend will
continue let's move on to
portfolio this is a collection of
Investments such as stocks bonds and
other assets held by an individual or
entity to achieve diversification and
manage risk in their overall investment
strategy portfolio diversification
involves spreading your Investments
across different asset classes such as
stocks bonds and real estate to reduce
risk as different types of Investments
May perform differently under various
ious economic conditions ultimately
helping to achieve a more balanced and
stable investment
strategy stocks analysis is the process
of evaluating stocks for investment
often using fundamental and technical
analysis let's take a look at some of
the way stocks are
valued first up we have the PE ratio
this is price to earnings ratio this
valuation metric is calculated by
dividing a Stock's price by its earnings
per
share another analysis metric is market
capitalization when you multiply the
stock price by the number of shares you
get the total value of a company's
outstanding shares of stock
[Music]
next up we have some trading
terminology Blue Chip stocks are stocks
of well large established companies with
a history of stable
performance day trading is the practice
of buying and selling stocks within the
same trading day
let's move on to our next term which is
Bid And ask
prices the bid price is the maximum
price a buyer is willing to pay for a
stock while the ask price is the minimum
price a seller is willing to
accept the difference between them is
known as the bid ask spread
[Music]
the term volume refers to the total
number of shares traded in a specific
stock or the entire Market within a
given time frame it can indicate the
level of interest and liquidity in a
[Music]
stock a market order is an instruction
to buy or sell a stock immediately at
the current market price it guarantees
execution but may not guarantee a
specific
[Music]
price a limit order is an order to buy
or sell a stock at a specific price or
better it ensures a specific price but
does not guarantee execution if the
market price doesn't reach the limit
price
[Music]
a stoploss order is a predefined price
level at which a stock is automatically
sold to limit potential losses it's a
riskmanagement tool used by
Traders when it comes to the stock
market there are two different types of
investors a retail investor is an
investor who buys and sell stocks for
personal
portfolios while institutional investors
are usually large organizations like
mutual funds or Pension funds that
invest on behalf of
others and that wraps up our vocabulary
lesson on the stock market I hope you
found it interesting we've covered some
essential terms to help you navigate
this Dynamic Financial world with
confidence
[Music]
today we've got an essential vocabulary
lesson on real estate so if you're ready
let's dive in our first term for our
real estate vocabulary is
property property refers to physical
assets such as land buildings and
everything permanently attached to them
these can include residential homes
commercial spaces and even on developed
land understanding the concept of
property is fundamental to navigating
the real estate
World a mortgage is a financial
Arrangement where A lender provides you
with the necessary funds to purchase a
property and you repay this loan over
time with interest it's a significant
part of the home buying process and
involves understanding terms like
interest rates Deb payments and Loan
duration next up we have the term
landlord or land lady land lady really
isn't used that much anymore landlord is
a common term that you can use for both
genders the landlord is the individual
or entity who owns the property you are
renting or leasing they are responsible
for maintaining the property and
ensuring your compliance with the lease
agreement knowing the rights and
responsibilities of both landlords and
tenants is crucial for a smooth renting
experience and let's check out this term
tenant as a tenant you are the renter or
occupant of a property owned by a
landlord tenants pay rent to landlords
in exchange for the use of the
property an important term in real
estate is lease a lease is a legally
binding contract that outlines the terms
and conditions of your tency it
specifies the duration of your stay rent
payments and any rules or regulations
you must follow while living in the
rented property leases can vary in
length and complexity so it's important
to thoroughly read and understand the
terms before
signing Residential Properties are real
estate assets designed for living such
as houses apartments and
Condominiums while commercial property
refers to real estate specifically used
for business or income generating
purposes this category includes
properties like Office Buildings retail
spaces industrial facilities and
warehouses let's move on to investment
property these are real estate assets
purchased with the intention of
generating income or making a profit
these can include rental properties
commercial real estate or properties
bought for future resale knowledge of
investment property strategies is
essential for Real Estate Investors and
real estate
agents a real estate agent is a
professional who assists individuals in
buying or selling property they have a
deep knowledge of the local real estate
market and their expertise is invaluable
when navigating the complexities of real
estate
transactions an appraisal is a
professional assessment of a property's
value it is often conducted when buying
or refinancing a property an appraisal
is often carried out by a real estate
agent let's move along to our next term
foreclosure foreclosures happen when a
property is repossessed by the lender
due to the borrower's failure to make
mortgage payments it is a legal process
that can result in the property being
sold at
auction we are working our way through
the word list but don't forget I have a
wide range of videos covering different
types of property Investments available
on my channel page and I have some of
them Linked In the video description
below make sure to check them out
let's move on to the term Equity this is
the difference between the current
market value of a property and the
outstanding balance of the mortgage it
represents the homeowner's ownership
stake in the property and can increase
over time as the mortgage is paid down
and the property's value
appreciates closing costs are the
expenses associated with finalizing a
real estate transaction
they include fees for services like
title searches appraisals and legal
services buyers and sellers need to be
aware of these costs as they can
significantly affect the overall cost of
a real estate
transaction a title is a legal document
that proves ownership of a property it
includes details about the property's
history an elans and the current own
owner ensuring the title is in order is
essential to avoid potential legal
disputes when buying or selling real
estate in British English a title would
be called a
deed the down payment is the initial
payment made by the buyer when
purchasing a property it's typically
expressed as a percentage of the
property's purchase price once the dam
payment is paid the house or property is
secured for the
buyer a home inspection is a thorough
examination of a property's condition
usually conducted by a licensed
inspector it helps buyers identify any
potential issues or needed repairs
before finalizing a purchase a quality
Home Inspection can save buyers from
unexpected costs and problems
[Music]
today we're diving into the world of
mortgages and exploring some Essential
Mortgage terms whether you're a
firsttime home buyer or simply looking
to understand the process better this
video is for
you our first term is the subject of our
video mortgage a mortgage is a legal
agreement between a borrower and A
lender typically a bank that allows the
borrower to obtain funds to purchase a
home the property itself self serves as
collateral for the loan and the borrower
makes regular payments including
principal and interest until the loan is
paid
off next up we have principal the
principal is the initial amount borrowed
in a mortgage it's the base amount on
which interest is calculated over time
as you make payments the principal
balance
decreases moving on to to interest rates
this is the cost of borrowing money
expressed as a percentage it determines
how much you'll pay in interest over the
life of your mortgage interest rates can
be fixed or
adjustable a fixed rate mortgage has a
consistent interest rate throughout the
life of the loan it offers stability and
predictable monthly
payments on the other hand an adjustable
rate mortgage or a variable rate
mortgage has an interest rate that may
change periodically it often starts with
a lower rate but can increase over
time the fixed rate period in an
adjustable rate mortgage is the initial
period during which the interest rate
remains fixed before it begins to adjust
periodically
let's move on to down payment the down
payment is the initial amount paid by
the home buyer when purchasing a
property it's typically a percentage of
the home's purchase price and a larger
Dam payment often leads to more
favorable mortgage
terms our next term is
amortization it's the process of paying
off your mortgage over time through
regular payments which include both
principal and interest over the life of
the loan the proportion of principle and
interest in each payment
changes let's discuss escrow an escrow
account is set up to hold funds for
property taxes and insurance part of
your monthly mortgage payment goes into
this account to ensure these expenses
are paid when due
next up closing costs these are fees and
expenses associated with finalizing a
mortgage and the purchase of a home
closing costs include charges for
services such as appraisal title search
and legal
fees if you're interested in learning
lots more related English vocabulary
check the links on screen and in my
video description on my channel I have
lots of English vocabulary videos
relating to banking Finance Investments
real estate and lots
more let's get back to our lesson and
our next term is
pre-approval this is a crucial step in
the home buying process it is a
preliminary assessment by the lender
that determines how much you can borrow
this helps you understand your budget
and increases your chances when buying a
new home
PMI or private mortgage insurance is
insurance that lenders require from
borrowers who make a down payment of
less than 20% it protects the lender in
case the borrower defaults on the
loan refinance refers to the process of
obtaining a new mortgage to replace an
existing one it's often done to secure a
better interest rate or to change the
terms of the
loan our next term is equity your Equity
is the portion of your home's value that
you own outright it's the difference
between the home's current market value
and the outstanding balance on your
mortgage an appraisal is a professional
assessment of a property's value it's
often required by lenders to ensure the
properties's work is sufficient to cover
the loan
[Music]
amount foreclosure is a legal process in
which a lender takes possession of a
property due to the borrower's failure
to meet their mortgage obligations it
typically leads to the sale of the
property to recover the loan
amount our next term is closing
disclosure this is a document provided
to the borrower at least three days
before the mortgage closing it outlines
the final terms and costs of the loan
ensuring transparency in the
transaction title insurance is a policy
that protects the homeowner and the
lender from Financial loss due to
disputes or defects in the property's
title it ensures that the property has a
clear and marketable
title the mortgage origination fee is a
charge imposed by the lender to cover
the cost of processing and underwriting
the loan it's typically a percentage of
the loan
amount a home equity line of credit is a
type of loan that allows homeowners to
borrow against the equity in their home
it provides a flexible source of funds
that can be drawn upon as
needed understanding these mortgage
terms is crucial for making informed
decisions when buying a
[Music]
home in today's lesson we'll be diving
into a topic That's essential for many
of us buying a car whether you're a
beginner or looking to enhance your
English this lesson will equip you with
the necessary vocabulary and phrases for
this important
activity let's begin with some essential
car buying vocabulary remember you can
always pause and Rewind the video to
practice these words and
phrases let's look firstly at different
types of cars which people commonly
buy this is a sedan a sedan is a foro
passenger car with a trunk or boot that
is separate from the passenger's
compartment
our next car type is an SUV SUV stands
for sports utility vehicle it refers to
a type of car that sits high off the
ground and which often has four-wheel
drive and rugged
styling a convertible is a passenger car
that can be driven with or without a
roof in place the methods of retracting
and storing the roof vary among eras and
manufacturers a hatchback is a type of
car with a rear door that swings upwards
this provides access to a cargo area in
the main interior of the car rather than
a separated trunk like a
sedan and next up we have a pickup truck
or simply known as a pickup this is a
light duty truck that has an enclosed
cabin and it also has a back end made of
a cargo bed that is enclosed by three
low walls with no
roof let's move on to take a look at
some words relating to car
parts the heart of the car is the
engine this is the part that converts
the energy of the fuel into mechanical
energy and produces the power which
makes the car move forward or backwards
in a car a transmission or a gearbox
acts as the medium that transmits power
generated by the engine to the wheels
via a mechanical system of gears and
gear
trains a brake is the mechanical device
in a car that stops motion by absorbing
energy from a moving
system the steering wheel is the wheel
that a driver rotates in order to steer
or drive a car the steering wheel is
connected to the dashboard the dashboard
in a car is the panel facing the
driver's seat where most of the
instruments switches and information
are a car dashboard monitors vehicle
speed engine speed and engine
temperature a car's tires can be an
important consideration when Pur
purchasing this is the rubber covering
placed around a wheel to form a soft
contact with the road this word has
different spellings in American and
British English which you can see on
screen right
now let's move on and take a look at
some of the documents you may need when
thinking about getting a new
car the car registration is an important
document which registers your ownership
of the car with your local government
Authority a car title includes official
information about the vehicle and the
owner it differs from vehicle
registration and proof of insurance as
it's strictly proof of car
[Music]
ownership car insurance covers damage to
your vehicle and protects you
financially if you're liable for someone
else's injuries or damages
it can also pay for medical bills if you
or your passengers are injured in an
accident or if you're hit by a driver
who is uninsured or
underinsured a car loan is an agreement
between you and A lender that says they
will give you money to buy a car in
return you'll pay them back with
interest in an agreed upon period of
time if you're thinking of buying a car
the the place that you go is called a
car
dealership and the person that you buy
the car from is called a car
dealer different countries have
different rules but in lots of places
you can buy a car
secondhand this is where it has been
previously owned by someone else and
they will sell it to you at a discounted
price this is usually done online or
through local newspap papers and
[Music]
advertisements wherever you go you're
going to need some handy English phrases
to get your dream car so let's take a
look at some
now something you would say to start the
conversation with a car dealer is I'm in
the market for a new
car repeat the phrase after me I'm in
car if you see a car that you like and
you want to know how much it is you
would say what's the asking
price what's the asking
price when you're buying a new car you
can get the permission of the car
dealership to take it for a test drive
to do this you would simply say can I
take it for a test drive
please can I take it for a test drive
please if you need a loan to purchase
your car you can ask the car
dealership do you offer financing
do you offer
[Music]
financing lots of new cars and sometimes
secondhand cars will come with a
guarantee this means that if anything
goes wrong with the car within a certain
period of time the car dealership will
repair or replace the
parts if you want to check if your car
comes with this you could ask is there a
warranty is there a
[Music]
warranty so you see a car that you like
and you want to know more about it what
could you ask the
dealer hi I'm interested in the sedan
over there can you tell me more about
it listen and repeat after me hi I'm
interested in the sedan over there can
you tell me more about
[Music]
it so you found the car that you like
but the price is a little high if we
want the car for a cheaper price how may
we approach this with the car
dealer we could say the price seems a
bit high is there any room for
negotiation
[Music]
the price seems a bit high is there any
room for
[Music]
negotiation before we wrap up here are
some important tips when buying a car
number one research always research the
make and the model of the car you
want a budget is really important when
coming to buying a car so it's important
to set a budget a limit on what you want
to spend and stick to
[Music]
that if you find a car that you really
like make sure to check its vehicle
history this is an important check on
the car's history report it can tell you
things about the car that may change
your mind about buying
it when it comes to buying a secondhand
car it's important to get an inspection
this is having a trusted mechanic check
over the car to make sure everything is
[Music]
okay to guarantee a smooth sale ensure
all the documents we've discussed in
this lesson are in
order and that's it for today's lesson
on buying a car and essential vocabulary
and phrases I hope you found it
[Music]
helpful in this English lesson we'll be
taking a look at some intermediate
banking terms these terms are a little
bit more advanced but I will break them
down for you in the following ways for
each of the 15 banking terms you'll
learn today will cover pronunciation
definitions and example sentences so
with all of that business out of the way
let's begin our lesson on banking
terms our first term is mortgage now
this word has a silent T which I've
highlighted in the word let's check our
pronunciation
mortgage a mortgage is like a long-term
loan specifically for buying property
when you get a mortgage the bank lends
you the money to buy a house or
apartment and you agree to pay it back
over many years often 15 to 30 the
property itself serves as security for
the loan which means if you can't make
the payments the bank could take the
property
back let's move on and take a look at
our example
sentence after years of saving for a
down payment we're finally applying for
a mortgage to buy our dream
home our second term is equity repeat
after me
Equity think of equity as your piece of
a financial
pie for example if you own a house the
equity is the part of the House's value
that you actually own it's the
difference between the value of the
property and what you still owe on any
mortgages Equity can also refer to
ownership in a company through stocks
let's move on and take a look at our
example sentence I've been paying the
mortgage for 10 years so I've built up
considerable equity in my
house our next term is
collateral repeat after me
collateral collateral is something
valuable that you promise to give your
lender if you can't pay back a loan it's
like saying if I can't pay you back in
cash you can take this item instead
common examples of collateral include
houses cars or other valuable assets it
gives the lender assurance that they
will recover their money one way or
another so let's take this word
collateral and use it in an example
sentence to secure the loan for my
business I offered my vintage car as
collateral our fourth banking term is
asset management let's make sure we have
the pronunciation perfect Asset
Management asset management is all about
a professional managing your money and
Investments think of an asset manager as
a financial Chef they take your
ingredients like savings stocks and
bonds and cook up a plan to help your
wealth grow over time keeping in mind
your financial goals and risk
tolerance since I'm not an expert in
stocks and bonds I rely on Asset
Management Services to handle my
Investment
Portfolio we'll cover this term
portfolio later in the lesson let's move
on to diversification repeat after me
divers
ification let's try it one more time
diversification diversification in
banking is like not putting all your
eggs in one basket it's spreading your
Investments across different types of
assets stocks bonds real estate Etc to
reduce risk if one investment performs
poorly others might do well and buy
balance things
out our example
sentences my financial advisor suggested
diversification of my investments to
protect against Market
swings our sixth term is
liability repeat after me
liability in banking a liability is
essentially any money you owe this could
be a Loan mortgage or even money you've
PR promise to pay in the future it's an
obligation you're legally required to
fulfill understanding your liabilities
is crucial for managing your Financial
Health right now paying off my credit
card debt is my Main Financial
liability our seventh banking term is
credit rating repeat after me credit
rating your credit r rating is a score
that tells lenders how good you are at
paying back money you've borrowed it's
like a report card for your finances a
high credit rating means you're a
lowrisk borrower which can help you get
loans with better interest rates on the
other hand a low credit rating can make
borrowing more expensive or even
impossible let's check out our example
sentence I'm working to improve my
credit rating by paying bills on time
and reducing my debt let's check out the
pronunciation of our next term
principal
principle in the context of banking the
principle is the original sum of money
borrowed in a loan or the amount of the
investment it doesn't include the
interest or additional fees so when you
start repaying a loan part of your
payments go go towards reducing the
principal and part go towards the
interest over time as I keep making
payments on my car loan the principal
amount
decreases our ninth term is annual
percentage rate often referred to as AP
or so we have annual percentage rate or
apor AP or is like the true cost of
borrowing money expressed as a yearly
interest rate it includes not just the
interest rate but also any additional
fees or charges associated with the loan
so it's a more complete picture of what
you'll actually
pay when comparing Loan offers I always
check the APR to understand the full
cost of
borrowing another important banking term
is compound interest
repeat after me compound
interest compound interest is when you
earn interest not just on your initial
investment or principle but also on the
interest that has been added to it over
time it's like your savings growing
exponentially because the interest you
earn each year also starts earning
interest thanks to compound interest my
savings account balance has grown more
than I had initially
calculated let's move on to our next
term which is liquid
assets repeat after me liquid
assets liquid assets are things you own
that can be quickly and easily turned
into Cash without losing value this
includes things like money in savings
accounts or stocks that can be sold on
short notice they're called liquid
because because they can flow easily
into
cash I always keep a portion of my
investments in liquid assets for
emergencies next up we're going to look
at two different types of interest rate
first up we have fixed interest rate
repeat after me fixed interest
rate a fixed interest rate means the
interest rate on your loan or savings
account won't change over a set period
it's predictable like a fixed menu in a
restaurant you know exactly what you're
getting and what it will cost you with
no
surprises our example sentences I chose
a loan with a fixed interest rate so my
monthly repayments will stay the same
the other type of interest rate is a
variable interest rate repeat after me
variable interest rate
in contrast to the fixed interest rate a
variable interest rate can change over
time based on the market or an index
it's a bit like the weather sometimes
it's sunny rates go down and sometimes
it's rainy rates go up this can affect
your loan payments or savings
earnings my mortgage has a variable
interest rate so my payments might
fluctuate over the years our penultimate
banking term is bankruptcy let's check
our pronunciation one more time
bankruptcy bankruptcy is a legal process
where people or businesses that can't
pay their debts get a fresh start the
process involves legally declaring the
inability to pay off debts while it can
relieve debt pressure it also impacts
credit ratings and the ability to borrow
in the
future let's use bankrupt
in an example sentence the company filed
for bankruptcy after failing to recover
from its Financial
losses our final banking term is
portfolio repeat after me
portfolio your portfolio is the
collection of all your Investments like
stocks bonds real estate Etc a well
Diversified portfolio is key to managing
risk and achieving your financial goals
let's check out our final example
sentence my financial advisor helps me
manage my Investment Portfolio to ensure
it aligns with my long-term goals
[Music]